........
。。。。。。。。
Now, let us host the next broadcast, Ms. Wang Fan Sheng vice director
では、次の放送の司会をしましょう、副ディレクターの王範生さん
Please give him a round of applause
彼に拍手をお願いします
Welcome Professor Qu and fellow individuals
Qu 教授とその仲間たちを歓迎します
Our knowledge feast is a very important event for our hospital to promote popular science facts
私たちの知識の饗宴は、私たちの病院にとって一般的な科学事実を宣伝する非常に重要なイベントです
Every month we invite lifted scholars from inside and outside the academy
毎月、学院内外から有資格者を招聘しています
Experts come here to talk about the latest academic developments
専門家がここに集まり、最新の学術開発について話します
Today, there are 1.3 or 1.4 times in each month here are humanities and social sciences
現在、人文科学と社会科学は月に 1.3 ～ 1.4 回あります。
It's all hosted by me in the Humanities and Social Sciences Association
私は人文社会科学協会の主催者です
Today we are very honored to invite Professor Xu Wanwen from the Humanities and Social Sciences Research Center of our school to give a speech
本日は、本校人文社会科学研究センターの徐万文教授をお招きして講演をしていただけることを大変光栄に思います。
Professor Xu Wanwen is a graduate of the Department of Economics, National Taiwan University
Xu Wanwen教授は国立台湾大学経済学部卒業生です。
After graduation, he went to Stanford University in the United States to obtain a Ph.D. in Finance
卒業後はアメリカのスタンフォード大学に進学し、金融学の博士号を取得しました。
Once taught at the University of Notre Dame and the University of California, Los Angeles
かつてノートルダム大学とカリフォルニア大学ロサンゼルス校で教鞭をとったことがある
He also served as the deputy counseling secretary of the academic counseling association of the college
また、本学の学術相談協会の副相談事務局長も務めました。
And there is a fertility support to see me
そして、私に会うための妊孕性サポートがあります
Editor-in-Chief and Deputy Consultant of Taiwan Social Research Institute
台湾社会研究所編集長兼副顧問
Professor Xu is also in the Economics Department of National Taiwan University
Xu教授は国立台湾大学経済学部にも在籍しています
National Taiwan University Physiognomy Institute
国立台湾大学生理学研究所
Chuo University's Industrial Economics Institute
中央大学産業経済研究所
part-time professor
兼任教授
Professor Xu's research seems to me
徐教授の研究は私にはそう思えます
There is one point worth pointing out again.
もう一度指摘しておきたい点があります。
Just when everyone is being very small
ちょうどみんながとても小さくなったときに
when limited in here
ここに制限がある場合
It's a minority that takes a lot of weight
非常に重要視されるのは少数派だ
Overall Industrial Economic Policy
産業経済政策全般
Scholars with Industrial Economic Development
産業経済発展を担う学者
so its writings
だからその文章は
including many
多くを含めて
Among them, the following public language matters
その中で、今回の公式声明は、
Alternative Thoughts on Taiwan's Economic Development
台湾の経済発展に関する別の考え
Taiwan's economy under globalization
グローバル化下の台湾経済
Mechanisms of economic growth, etc.
経済成長の仕組みなど
in 2003
2003年に
it collaborates with an american scholar
アメリカの学者と共同研究している
A special book on the study of Taiwan's industrial upgrading
台湾の産業高度化を研究する専門書
Published immediately from the public circle in the United States
米国の公的サークルから即時に出版
There are many other works
他にもたくさんの作品があります
These works are all about the upgrading of the industry
これらの作品はすべて業界のアップグレードに関するものです
Post-war economic development and other related issues
戦後の経済発展とそれに関連する問題
In recent years, Professor Qi has also begun to conduct
近年、Qi教授はまた、
Research on China's economic development model after the reform and opening up
改革開放後の中国の経済発展モデルに関する研究
he is in this
彼はこの中にいます
When I talked about the economic development of East Asia and other areas
東アジアなどの経済発展について話したとき
All Fertility Scholars
すべての不妊研究者
Today he is coming to share with you a speech
今日彼はあなたにスピーチをするために来ています
After the inheritance of the Republic of China
中華民国継承後
The Inheritance of the Republic of China and the Post-war Economic Development of Taiwan
中華民国の継承と台湾の戦後経済発展
I think we have a lot to look forward to today's speech
今日のスピーチはとても楽しみにしていると思います
We now welcome Professor Qi with warm applause
チー教授を温かい拍手でお迎えいたします
Thank you Dean of Protection
保護部長、ありがとう
Thank you so much for listening to me so late
遅くまで話を聞いていただき、本当にありがとうございました
come hear me say something
私の言うことを聞きに来てください
my research results
私の研究結果
The topic I want to talk about today is the inheritance of the Republic of China and Taiwan's post-war economic development
本日お話したいテーマは、中華民国の継承と台湾の戦後経済発展についてです。
Let me first explain why I want to talk about this topic
まず最初に、なぜこのトピックについて話したいのかを説明します
This is of course related to my recent research
もちろんこれは私の最近の研究に関連しています
After I returned to Taiwan more than 20 years ago
20年以上前に台湾に戻ってから
Let me start first, as Wang Fu just mentioned
先ほど王福が言ったように、まず始めましょう
I study Taiwan
台湾を勉強しています
Comparing recent economic development in the last 30 years
過去30年間の最近の経済発展を比較してみる
especially
特に
Shangde Instrument is the industrial upgrading of Taiwan's high-tech industry in the past 20 years
上徳計器は過去 20 年間に台湾のハイテク産業を高度化させた企業です
But the more I research, the more I feel that we
しかし、調べれば調べるほど、私たちは
It seems that Taiwan's economy has arrived
台湾経済も元気になってきたようです
The recent transformation
最近の変革
is in a bind
窮地に陥っている
That's the dilemma with its big background
それが大きな背景を持つジレンマです
So I gradually started to watch
それで徐々に見始めました
Taiwan
台湾
just want to ask
ただ聞きたいだけです
The further issue is Taiwan's post-war economic development
さらに問題となるのは台湾の戦後の経済発展である。
how did it start
どのようにして始まりましたか
The more I research, the more interesting and complicated this problem seems to be.
研究を進めていくうちに、この問題はより興味深く複雑であることがわかりました。
So I became like half a historian
それで私は半分歴史家になった
Maybe historians don't agree
おそらく歴史家は同意しないでしょう
But at least I also started to publish an article in Taiwan History Research
しかし、少なくとも私は台湾歴史研究にも記事を掲載し始めました
Also published an article in New Historiography
『New Historiography』にも記事を掲載
even if the field isn't very... how to say
たとえその分野があまり良くなくても...なんて言うのでしょう？
not taken seriously
真剣に受け止められていない
But more and more I feel like looking at these things from a historical perspective
しかし、ますますこれらのことを歴史的な観点から見てみたいと思うようになりました
is very important and very rewarding
とても重要でとてもやりがいのあることです
At the same time, I found it difficult to say things at the beginning.
同時に、最初は物事を言うのが難しいと感じました。
That's me
それは私です
The industrial upgrading of Taiwan's high-tech industry is not easy
台湾のハイテク産業の産業高度化は容易ではない
But it is in the past sixty years
しかし、それは過去60年間のことです
Especially what can only happen on the basis of electricity in the past thirty years
特に、過去 30 年間に電気に基づいてのみ起こりえたこと
So I went back and studied the first thirty years
それで私は戻って最初の30年間を研究しました
From 1945, 1949
1945年～1949年
especially
特に
So I've been focusing on the 1950s lately
そこで最近は1950年代に注目しています
Taiwan's post-war economic development
台湾の戦後の経済発展
how did it start
どのようにして始まりましたか
So this is what I've been doing for about ten years
これが私が10年ほど続けていることです
a focused study
集中的な勉強
then my research today
それから今日の私の研究
In particular it will be
特にそうなります
how to explain
どのように説明するか
Taiwan's postwar economic development
台湾の戦後の経済発展
this motive
この動機
quite complicated
かなり複雑な
that's what i found out
それが私が知ったことです
In the process of democratization in Taiwan
台湾の民主化の過程で
how to explain
どのように説明するか
Taiwan's Postwar Economic Development
台湾の戦後経済発展
In fact, there is a mainstream argument
実は主流の議論がある
there for
そこに
Legacy of Japanese Colonization
日本の植民地化の遺産
special affirmation
特別な肯定
Also highly affirmed the role of the United States
米国の役割も高く評価
It is also highly negative for the national government
国家政府にとっても非常にマイナスだ
I'm a little confused about this situation
この状況については少し混乱しています
I also feel
私も感じます
Backward countries all over the world must go through a process of decolonization
世界中の後進国は脱植民地化のプロセスを経なければなりません
That is to say, backward countries were more or less former colonies
つまり、後進国は多かれ少なかれ元植民地だったということです。
then how do you develop your own economy
ではどうやって独自の経済を発展させるのか
How to face your colonial experience in this process
このプロセスにおいて植民地時代の経験とどう向き合うか
is a serious challenge
深刻な挑戦です
I'm disturbed by how much I think about the present
現在のことを考えすぎて不安になる
For example, to give a very simple example
たとえば、非常に簡単な例を挙げると、
this May
今年の5月
In order to commemorate the designer of the Jianan Army
嘉南軍の設計者を記念して
Batian language also see
バティアン語も参照
his memorial park
彼の記念公園
into his memorial
彼の記念碑に
President Ma also attended in person
馬総統も直接出席した
The whole discourse is very grateful to him
講演全体が彼にとても感謝しています
then i was thinking
それから私は考えていました
then we know
そうすればわかります
What reservoir and who built it?
何の貯水池で、誰がそれを建設しましたか?
we for
私たちはのために
Who built such a reservoir?
誰がこんな貯水池を建てたのでしょうか？
do we know
私たちは知っていますか
are we grateful
私たちは感謝していますか
Is there any criticism?
批判はありますか？
so
それで
This makes me feel like saying
こう言いたくなる
haven't we done it yet
まだやってないのか
be humble
謙虚になりなさい
to review
レビューする
to confront past colonial experience
過去の植民地時代の経験と向き合う
this is not just
これだけではありません
that's all
それで全部です
Because what I'm trying to say here is to say
なぜなら、私がここで言いたいのは、
This is the same as our current
これは今の私たちと同じです
Economic and political difficulties are related
経済的および政治的困難は関連している
then i hope
それなら私は願っています
after i speak
私が話した後
can convince everyone
誰もが納得できる
maybe it has something to do with it
もしかしたらそれと関係があるかもしれない
I guess part of this dilemma
このジレンマの一部だと思います
I think you don't need me to say more
これ以上言う必要はないと思います
everyone will agree
誰もが同意するだろう
That is to say, it is a political dilemma
つまり、政治的なジレンマです
not what i want to say
私が言いたいことではない
But with the political dilemma
しかし、政治的なジレンマを抱えて
We also have our economic difficulties
私たちにも経済的困難があります
We lack economic vision
私たちには経済的ビジョンが欠けています
We also lack how to go
私たちも行き方が足りない
pursuing economic vision
経済的ビジョンの追求
economic policy
経済政策
At the same time I don't know if you have noticed
同時に、あなたが気づいたかどうかはわかりませんが、
we don't talk much these days
最近はあまり話さない
a concept called economic vision
経済ビジョンという概念
no one talks
誰も話さない
This is of course a very dangerous thing
もちろんこれはとても危険なことです
I call this an economic dilemma
私はこれを経済的ジレンマと呼んでいます
What I'm going to say today is to say
今日私が言おうとしていることは、
why are we like this
なぜ私たちはこうなっているのか
I certainly wish to say that if I
私だったら確かにそう言いたいです
My research is hoping to clarify this issue
私の研究はこの問題を解明することを望んでいます
then help us to be able to
それから私たちができるように手伝ってください
then go
それから行きます
ok, let me talk about it first
わかりました、最初に話しましょう
that is
あれは
Taiwanese society
台湾社会
Of course we are in Taiwan
もちろん台湾にいますよ
have a lot of grades
たくさんの成績を持っている
for a while
しばらくの間
we'll be called say
私たちはそう呼ばれるでしょう
we have double miracle
私たちには二重の奇跡があります
our economy is a miracle
私たちの経済は奇跡です
then for a while
それからしばらくの間
we are very gentle
私たちはとても優しいです
means of peace
平和の手段
achieved democratization
民主化を達成した
Also considered a miracle of democracy
民主主義の奇跡とも考えられる
So we say it's
だから私たちはこう言います
Tin-Lirical Double Miracle
ブリキリリカルダブルミラクル
very proud achievement
非常に誇らしい成果
but everything
でもすべて
seems to have its price
それなりの値段があるようだ
then we are
それなら私たちは
i'm here to say
私は言うためにここにいます
as we democratize
私たちが民主化するにつれて
our society
私たちの社会
a mainstream discourse
主流の言説
very powerful
とてもパワフルな
it goes deep
それは深くなる
but it doesn't
しかしそうではありません
We ask which scholar
どの学者に尋ねます
Did this write a book?
この人は本を書きましたか？
Which scholar has established a scholarly basis for this without
何もせずにこのことの学術的根拠を確立した学者は誰ですか？
but but everyone knows
でもでもみんな知ってるよ
it's baby talk
それは赤ちゃん言葉です
Can't bear it
我慢できない
good
良い
Okay, let me briefly talk about the economic part
さて、経済的な部分について簡単に話しましょう
The prevailing discourse goes like this
主流の言説はこんな感じ
is how to explain Taiwan's economic miracle
台湾の経済奇跡をどう説明するか
Because that part should be undeniable anyway
どうせその部分は否定できないはずだから
that would say
それは言うだろう
It should be the credit of Japanese colonial rule
それは日本の植民地支配の功績であるべきだ
or american role
またはアメリカ人の役割
If you don't want to be sure about this
これについて確かめたくない場合は、
That means the people work very hard
それは人々がとても一生懸命働いていることを意味します
The most important part is the negative part
最も重要な部分はネガティブな部分です
It is to deny the contribution of the Kuomintang and the National Government
国民党と国民政府の貢献を否定するものである。
Although it is said that economic development should be the responsibility of the national government
経済発展は国の責任だと言われていますが、
The best piece in the first year after the war
戦後最初の最高傑作
All other parts are subject to these discounts
他のすべての部品はこれらの割引の対象となります
This argument holds that the Kuomintang, for its own benefit,
この主張は、国民党が自らの利益のために、
Established a monopoly party-state capital
独占政党・国家資本を設立
Obstructing the private sector is of no use to Taiwan
民間部門の妨害は台湾にとって役に立たない
So it emphasizes the opposition to party-state authoritarianism
したがって、政党国家権威主義への反対を強調しています。
emphasis on nativism
強調本土主義
Then with this support is
そして、このサポートにより、
The neoliberalism of our economics
私たちの経済学の新自由主義
Compared with mainstream discourses in Taiwanese society
台湾社会の主流の言説との比較
Blue Camp is basically
ブルーキャンプは基本的に
no words no discussion
言葉も議論もなし
ok then let's take a look
わかりました、それでは見てみましょう
this
これ
Taiwan economy
台湾経済
Development achievements
開発実績
From the perspective of the world
世界から見ると
how
どうやって
ok this is
わかりました、これは
Medicine
薬
experts in this field
この分野の専門家
he is very powerful
彼はとてもパワフルです
all countries in the world
世界のすべての国
this thousand years
この千年
a thousand years
千年
All GDP counted
すべてのGDPがカウントされる
So my reliability
だから私の信頼性は
Nobody knows
誰も知らない
But it's our only basis
でもそれが私たちの唯一の根拠なのです
In recent decades
ここ数十年の間
Of course, the World Bank and the IMF
もちろん世界銀行やIMFも
have some estimates
いくつかの見積もりがある
But you said this hundred years
でもあなたはこう言いました、百年後
We can only see him for a thousand years
私たちは彼を千年間見守ることしかできない
ok let's see
わかりました、見てみましょう
Postwar 1950 to 1998
戦後 1950 年から 1998 年
he provided us
彼は私たちに提供してくれました
Global We Divide Western Europe
世界を分断する西ヨーロッパ
United States Latin America Eastern Europe All Soviet Union
米国 ラテンアメリカ 東ヨーロッパ 全ソビエト連邦
Africa East Asia
アフリカ 東アジア
1950 1998
1950年1998年
their real per capita income
彼らの一人当たりの実質収入
let's take a look
見てみましょう
Taiwan in 1950 was 936 yuan
1950年の台湾は936元
It was a certain one in 1990
1990年のとあるものでした
Let's count it in dollars.
ドルで数えてみましょう。
We saw
私たちは見た
one tenth
10分の1
By 1998
1998年までに
It is about 55% of the United States
それはアメリカの約55％です
We can see that
それがわかります
I'm going to show you the Philippines
フィリピンを紹介します
in 1950
1950年に
The Philippines was a role model for Taiwan at that time
フィリピンは当時の台湾にとって模範となった
just younger friends
ただ年下の友達だけ
probably unbelievable
おそらく信じられない
but at that time
しかしその時は
The per capita income of the Philippines is higher than that of Taiwan
フィリピンの一人当たり所得は台湾より高い
And everyone thinks that the Philippines
そして誰もがフィリピンだと思っています
that time
その時
If we look at the remarks at that time
その時の発言を見てみると
Everyone thinks that the Philippines is more advanced
誰もがフィリピンの方が先進的だと思っている
Everyone remembers he was an American colony
誰もが彼がアメリカの植民地だったことを覚えている
But in this nearly 50 years
しかし、この50年近くの間に
in that time
その時
The Philippines has only grown
フィリピンは成長するばかり
only doubled
2倍になっただけ
But Taiwan's per capita income has increased by 16 times
しかし台湾の一人当たり所得は16倍に増加
let's take a look at that
それを見てみましょう
economic development
経済発展
So economic development is a
したがって、経済発展とは、
how to say
どのように言って
a catching up process
追いつくプロセス
In other words, you take the developing countries of Western Europe, America and Japan as a goal to catch up with them
つまり、西欧、アメリカ、日本といった発展途上国に追いつくことを目標にしているということですね。
So if you look at Western Europe and the United States, they are very mature
西ヨーロッパとアメリカを見ると、彼らは非常に成熟しています。
So the multiple of their growth is more than three times
つまり、成長の倍数は 3 倍以上になります
Latin America's development is ahead of ours
ラテンアメリカの発展は私たちの前にあります
But its development is also quite
しかしその展開もなかなかのもの
Not developing well during this time
この時期は成長がうまくいかない
It only grew 2.3 times
2.3倍しか増えなかった
Eastern Europe and the Soviet Union are backward
東欧とソ連は後進国だ
Africa is also behind
アフリカも遅れている
Therefore, the countries in East Asia can be said to be an exception in the backward countries
したがって、東アジア諸国は後進国の例外であると言えます。
That is, the speed of growth far exceeds the goal we want to catch up with.
つまり、追いつきたい目標をはるかに上回る成長スピードです
Therefore, we have successfully shortened the distance between us and the target we want to catch up with.
したがって、追いつきたいターゲットとの距離を縮めることに成功しました。
Among the backward countries, very few
後進国の中で、
In the next 50 to 60 years, there are very few backward countries that have achieved this goal
今後50年から60年の間に、この目標を達成できる後進国はほとんどなくなるでしょう。
so
それで
let's look again
もう一度見てみましょう
Because the one just now was in 1998
さっきのは1998年だから
And then if we look at 2010 it's
そして 2010 年を見てみると、
The latest information we can have
私たちが知り得る最新の情報
Ranking of real GDP per capita of countries based on IMF
IMFが算出した各国の一人当たり実質GDPランキング
According to Purchasing Power Parity
購買力平価による
deflating purchasing power
購買力の低下
good
良い
We can see that Taiwan ranks 21
台湾が21位であることがわかります。
Then this value is very high
そうすると、この値は非常に高いです
More than 35,000 US dollars
35,000米ドル以上
This is a bit of a favor
これはちょっとしたお願いです
But I guess this is showing that
しかし、これはそれを示していると思います
In fact, we are very used to
実際、私たちはとても慣れています
Our prices in Taiwan
台湾での価格
Very stable for decades
数十年にわたって非常に安定した
so everyone see
だからみんな見て
this japanese korean
この日本人韓国人
Japan we always feel that he should
日本では彼がそうすべきだといつも感じている
His Life Scholar should be higher than ours
彼の人生の学者は私たちの人生学者よりも優れているはずです
But maybe it's because he's too expensive
でも多分それは彼が高価すぎるからだろう
so he flattened out
それで彼は平らになった
still behind Taiwan
まだ台湾に遅れを取っている
so this is
それでこれは
If we remove the first 20 middle
最初の真ん中の20個を取り除くと
remove the words of several petro-states
いくつかの石油国家の言葉を削除する
Taiwan should be
台湾はそうあるべきだ
Ranked 17th
17位
ok so this is a
わかりました、これは
very remarkable achievement
非常に顕著な功績
Then this development
するとこの展開は
is also quite average
も非常に平均的です
is stable
安定しています
continuous
継続的な
Let's take a look at some important
いくつかの重要な点を見てみましょう
Economic Indicators
経済指標
Real GDP
実質GDP
the first 30 years
前30年
nearly 10% faster
ほぼ 10% 高速化
growing up
成長
So now everyone feels
だから今、誰もが感じている
Mainland China is amazing
中国本土はすごいよ
10% per year
10%/年
In fact, Taiwan was almost like this in the first 30 years
実際、台湾も最初の30年間はほぼこんな感じだった
no better than them
彼らよりも優れているわけではない
That is to say, it is developing surprisingly
つまり驚くほど発展しているのです
all at such a fast pace
すべてがとても速いペースで
growing up
成長
We're looking at him because of the slowing population growth
人口増加が鈍化しているため、私たちは彼に注目しています
so later
だから後で
This growth slows down
この成長は鈍化します
But our per capita GDP is still growing
しかし、一人当たりのGDPは依然として成長し続けています
OK, let's take a look at the price index at the end.
さて、最後に物価指数を見てみましょう。
that's what i just said
それが私が今言ったことです
Because of the national government's fear of quitting
政府が辞めるのを恐れているため
So the price stability is
したがって、価格の安定性は、
is a policy objective that they successfully achieved
政策目標は見事に達成された
that's what i think
それが私が思うことです
just why
なぜ
Why this real per capita GDP can rank among the best
この一人当たり実質 GDP がなぜ世界トップクラスにランクされるのか
It is also because our price level is quite stable
価格水準が非常に安定しているためでもあります
Okay, so this is the achievement of our economic development
なるほど、これが経済発展の成果ですね
That shouldn't be too much of a doubt
それはそれほど疑問に思うべきではない
an economic miracle
経済的な奇跡
Of course I won't say the other part
もちろん他の部分は言いません
That is to say, in the first thirty years
つまり最初の30年間は
The achievement of this economic development is also
この経済発展の成果も、
but with fairly average
しかしかなり平均的
and more average
そしてより平均的な
status of distribution
配布状況
good
良い
Let me talk about my structure first
まず私の構造について話させてください
that is
あれは
How does the country develop economy
その国はどうやって経済発展するのか
Let's look at East Asia as a
東アジアを次のように見てみましょう。
few exceptions
いくつかの例外
what conditions are needed
どのような条件が必要か
We know that the road mutual countries have to learn
私たちは両国が学ばなければならない道を知っています
Western advanced production methods
西洋の先進的な生産方法
their productivity
彼らの生産性
their technology
彼らの技術
how they are organized
どのように組織されているか
their business management
彼らの経営管理
we all have to learn
私たちは皆学ばなければなりません
But it's important to say
しかし、言うことが重要です
Although we have to learn
私たちは学ばなければなりませんが、
But we have to learn by ourselves
しかし、私たちは自分自身で学ばなければなりません
That is to say, we need to have our own space
つまり、自分専用のスペースが必要です
to develop your abilities
自分の能力を開発するために
grow our democratic industries
民主的な産業を成長させる
democratic business
民主的なビジネス
at this initial stage
この初期段階では
we need to get together
私たちは集まる必要があります
We need to resist this external force
私たちはこの外力に抵抗する必要があります
because especially when you start
なぜなら、特に始めたときは
Your strength is so far apart
あなたの強さは遠く離れています
That is to say, for example, during the Japanese occupation
つまり、例えば日本統治時代には
Why Taiwan's local power
なぜ台湾のローカルパワーなのか
The power of industry developed so little
産業の力はほとんど発展していなかった
It was also because of the advanced power of Japan at that time
それは当時の日本の先進国力の賜物でもありました。
is so far away
とても遠いです
Then you don't get policy support
そうなると政策のサポートが受けられなくなる
But it's important to say
しかし、言うことが重要です
You must have such a motivation
きっとそういうモチベーションがあるんだろうね
a wish
遺書
You have to make a vow that I will do this thing
あなたは私がこれをするという誓いを立てなければなりません
you need to be motivated
やる気が必要です
the will of such will
そのような意志の意志
I call this the will to develop
私はこれを発展意欲と呼んでいます
The Will to Develop
発展への意志
We in social science tend to think of ourselves
社会科学に携わる私たちは自分自身のことを考える傾向があります
become a science
科学になる
So don't talk about this
だからこのことについては話さないでください
this element of subjectivity
この主観の要素
but what i want to say
でも、私が言いたいことは
it exists
それが存在します
Then we social sciences can't
それでは私たち社会科学はそれができません
Truly claiming that we are science
私たちは科学であると真に主張する
We are between science and
私たちは科学と科学の間にいます
Between Science and Art
科学と芸術の間
that number
その番号
the other two conditions
他の2つの条件
is the ability to drive development
開発を推進する能力です
This is it
これだよ
is that you must be able to
それはあなたができる必要があるということです
go wrong about these things
これらのことに関して間違ってしまう
yes there
はい、そこです
The economy is dead
経済は死んでいる
can you handle it
対処できますか
let us pass safely
安全に通過しましょう
it takes ability
能力が必要です
that in addition
それに加えて
need some external conditions
何らかの外部条件が必要です
what i want to say is
私が言いたいのは
In the early postwar period in Taiwan
戦後初期の台湾
inherited by the national government
国に引き継がれる
The old kings of the Chinese nation survived in vain
中華民族の昔の王たちは無駄に生き残った
Chinese nationalism
中華民族主義
since the Opium War
アヘン戦争以来
so
それで
Developed over a hundred years
百年以上かけて発展してきた
Chinese nationalism
中華民族主義
plus
プラス
National Government
中央政府
Production and loan experience
制作・貸出実績
They brought their will to develop to Taiwan
彼らは発展への意志を台湾に持ち帰った
I'll wait for him to talk
彼が話すのを待ちます
what is the external condition
外部の状態は何ですか
So this is the architecture I explained
これが私が説明したアーキテクチャです
So the following I will order
そこで、以下を注文します
Discuss these in order
これらを順番に話し合う
I Japan's Colonial Influence on America's Role
I アメリカの役割に対する日本の植民地時代の影響
The actions of the national government and its will to develop
国の取り組みと発展への意志
Then I'll discuss the role of financial bureaucrats
次に財務官僚の役割についてお話します。
Then I have to give them a name
それから私は彼らに名前を付けなければなりません
Ruguan, who is called saving the country by industry, takes Ying Zhongrong as an example
産業で国を救うと称される如関氏は、例として英忠栄氏を例に挙げた。
Finally, let me discuss the development of the main body capacity and transformation of the new country.
最後に、本体能力の開発と新国家の変革について述べたいと思います。
So this is my content for today
それでは今日の内容はこれです
Okay, so let's talk about Japan's role first.
それでは、まず日本の役割について話しましょう。
Ok this one, I should all agree that Japan has done a lot of things in Taiwan
わかりました、日本が台湾で多くのことをしてきたということには全員が同意するはずです
Zhangliang land lays the foundation for modernization
張良の土地は近代化の基礎を築く
It not only paves the way, but also introduces and establishes a modern system
道を開くだけでなく、最新のシステムを導入し確立します。
with the organization
組織とともに
But he mainly puts this part in a global perspective first
しかし、彼は主にこの部分をグローバルな視点から最初に置きます
That is to say, the imperialists and colonists have arrived in the colonies
つまり、帝国主義者と植民地主義者が植民地に到着したということだ。
most of them do these things more or less
彼らのほとんどは多かれ少なかれこれらのことをします
I once read an article where he compares different colonies
彼がさまざまなコロニーを比較する記事を読んだことがあります
he has various indicators
彼はさまざまな指標を持っています
This is electricity, roads, what is the cost
これが力、道、コストは何ですか
What a bunch of indicators for universal education
普遍的な教育のための指標が何とたくさんあることか
Japan's colonies did not rank high on all indicators
日本の植民地はすべての指標で上位にランクされなかった
I remember that it is probably ranked first in Taiwan Electric Power
おそらく台湾電力では1位だったと記憶しています。
but generally good
しかし、一般的には良い
But it's not just Japanese imperialism doing this
しかし、これを行っているのは日本帝国主義だけではありません
Of course, the author thinks that the UK is also doing a good job.
もちろん、イギリスも頑張っていると筆者は思う。
he is an englishman
彼はイギリス人です
But he did collect those metrics for us
しかし、彼は私たちのためにそれらの指標を収集してくれました
Then there is a display saying
すると次のような表示が出ます
Indeed, in order to carry out his colonial enterprise in the colony, the colonist
実際、植民地で植民地事業を遂行するために、入植者は
he has to do these things too
彼はこれらのこともやらなければなりません
Well, so is Japan
まあ日本もそうだけど
He is in the colony of Taiwan
彼は台湾の植民地にいる
He mainly wants to turn Taiwan into a supplier of Mi Tang to Japan
彼は主に台湾を日本へのミータンの供給者にしたいと考えている
But he thus helped establish a modern agriculture in Taiwan
しかし、彼は台湾における近代農業の確立に貢献しました。
and then indeed successfully
そして実際に成功しました
Make Taiwan a base for supplying Mitang to Japan
台湾を日本への美唐供給拠点に
What we want to see is modernization and the establishment of modern industry
私たちが見たいのは近代化と近代産業の確立です
in previous decades
過去数十年間に
The modern industry established by Japan is mainly to control sugar
日本が確立した近代産業は主に砂糖の管理である
by the time the war started
戦争が始まるまでに
It did some military industrialization in Taiwan
台湾で軍事産業化を行った
but
しかし
According to scholars I respect
私が尊敬する学者によると
Soil feast
土教宴
he thinks that
彼はそう思う
because
なぜなら
Because Japan did not waver in Taiwan
日本は台湾でもブレなかったから
The most fundamental structure of the landlord economy
家主経済の最も基本的な構造
Then modern industries are all Japanese-funded
そうすると現代産業はすべて日本の資金で成り立っている
so he thinks
それで彼は考えます
He thinks Taiwan is not capitalized
彼は台湾は首都ではないと考えている
Industrialization started after the war
戦後に始まった工業化
Because modern industry is an enclave transplanted by Japan
近代産業は日本が移植した飛び地だから
The capital, technology and management personnel of modern industry are all Japanese
現代産業の資本も技術も経営人材もすべて日本人
And the Japanese education system is also compatible with this arrangement
そして日本の教育制度もこの仕組みに適合しています
doesn't train natives to do things like this
ネイティブにこのようなことをするように訓練しません
Therefore, the colonial government organization and the Japanese and Chinese natives occupied
したがって、植民地政府組織と日本人および中国人原住民が占領しました。
Occupies a relatively lower position
比較的低い位置を占めています
When it was accepted in 1945, people from the province who were appointed or above by the Japanese colonial government
1945年に受け入れられたときは、日本植民地政府によって任命された以上の州出身者が対象でした。
only 2.2%
わずか2.2%
The most famous is Zhu Congming's 11 professors
最も有名なのは朱従明の11人の教授です。
But of course the important thing is this
でももちろん大事なのはこれ
temporary mobilization system
臨時出動制度
Is a
です
is a totalitarian
全体主義者です
system of domination
支配のシステム
Because we know that the Japanese are temporarily
日本人が一時的にそうなっていることを知っているからです。
he gradually
彼は徐々に
further deprived the landowners of their power
地主からさらに権力を奪われた
So it is a highly mobilized system for war
つまり、戦争のために高度に動員されたシステムなのです
So he left a lot of room
それで彼はたくさんの余地を残した
Let the national government take over
国に引き継いでもらいましょう
But Taiwan is lucky
しかし台湾は幸運だ
Japan's colonists are defeated colonists
日本の植民地人は敗北した植民地人である
so he must evacuate completely
だから彼は完全に避難しなければならない
is his advanced economic power
彼の高度な経済力は
Including capital technology management talents
資本技術管理人材を含む
You could say he created a vacuum of talent at the top
彼はトップに才能の空白を生み出したと言えるだろう
But the entire advanced Japanese-owned enterprise
しかし、先進的な日系企業全体が
Advanced forces are also fully withdrawn
先進部隊も完全撤退
unlike in colonial times he was dominant
植民地時代とは異なり、彼は支配的だった
In the colonial period it was not only... I think it can be divided into two factors
植民地時代はそれだけではなかった…大きく2つの要因に分けられると思います
One is that Japanese companies are of course more advanced
一つは、もちろん日本企業の方が先進的であるということです。
The other is that the policy also highly restricts the development of local modern enterprises, at least in the early days.
もう 1 つは、この政策が、少なくとも初期においては、地元の近代的企業の発展を厳しく制限していることです。
Okay, so Taiwan is lucky in this respect that other backward regions do not have
さて、台湾は他の後進地域にはないこの点で幸運です。
the colonists are gone
入植者はいなくなった
We know many other colonists such as France who was defeated by Japan and kicked out of Vietnam
私たちは、日本に敗れてベトナムから追い出されたフランスなど、他にも多くの植民地人を知っています。
In the end, he actually said that he would return to Vietnam after four or five years.
結局、彼は4、5年後にベトナムに戻ると言いました。
Just reclam this place
この場所を埋め立ててください
But so this is, for example, like Indonesia
しかし、これはたとえばインドネシアのようなものです
He still has to fight a war with this Dutchman who was kicked out by the Japanese and came back
彼は日本軍に追い出されて戻ってきたこのオランダ人とまだ戦争をしなければならない
The independence movement of Indonesia is going to drive the Dutch out again and again
インドネシアのこの独立運動はオランダ人を何度も追い出すことになるだろう
Just like Vietnam
ベトナムみたいに
Well so not even if politics won the Revolutionary War politically
まあ、たとえ政治が独立戦争に政治的に勝ったとしてもそうではない
This one for the colonists is not necessarily going to exit economically
入植者向けのこれは必ずしも経済的に撤退するわけではない
Then Taiwan is our new master, the United States
その場合、台湾は我々の新たな主人、米国となる
Even the supporter behind the last one is also very tolerant
最後のサポーターもとても寛容です
For providing aid and also tolerating Taiwan's developmental state to promote industrialization
援助を提供し、工業化を促進する台湾の発展途上国を容認したことに対して
Then let me introduce a term called a developmental state
次に、発達状態という用語を紹介します。
In our social sciences, it is called
私たちの社会科学では、それはこう呼ばれています
development of state
国家の発展
refers to such a regime
そのような体制を指します
its ruler
その支配者
overall economic development
全体的な経済発展
priority target
優先目標
development priority
開発の優先順位
but very important
しかし、とても重要です
is that it is based on
に基づいているということです
Overall development is a priority
全体的な開発が優先事項です
rather than individual vested interests
個人の既得権益ではなく
I'll explain more later
後ほど詳しく説明します
ok that
わかりました、それは
Speaking of Japan
日本といえば
that this
これは
look at america
アメリカを見てください
of course we know
もちろん私たちは知っています
America after the war
戦後のアメリカ
very very important to Taiwan
台湾にとって非常に重要
we see this year
今年も見ます
The two presidential candidates are still going
2人の大統領候補はまだ続いている
American Chamber of Commerce
アメリカ商工会議所
speak in english
英語で話す
we know this
私たちはこれを知っています
The role of the United States is still very important
米国の役割は依然として非常に重要である
good
良い
Without the intervention of the United States
米国の介入がなければ
if
もしも
The Korean War didn't happen
朝鮮戦争は起こらなかった
america withdrew his support
アメリカは彼の支持を撤回した
Maybe we are busy with reform and opening up right now
おそらく今は改革開放で忙しいのでしょう。
so i tried this
それで私はこれを試しました
That is to say, the importance of the support of the United States
つまり、米国の支援の重要性である。
I think there is no doubt
間違いないと思います
After the Korean War
朝鮮戦争後
Military Aid Financial Aid Various
軍事援助 経済援助 各種
back again
再び
Of course in terms of financial aid
もちろん経済的援助の面でも
To stabilize Taiwan's economy
台湾経済の安定を目指して
is very important
はとても重要です
Because at that time inflation was
当時はインフレだったので、
tens of thousands
何万もの
But what I'm saying is
しかし、私が言っていることは、
We can't say these details
これらの詳細については言えません
but i want to point out that
しかし、私はそれを指摘したいと思います
we are now
私たちは今
are rarely able to go
めったに行けない
review
レビュー
Review our dependence on the United States
米国への依存を見直す
Review says Taiwan's dependence on US
レビューによると台湾は米国に依存している
Influence on the United States on Taiwan
米国が台湾に与える影響
That is a very big topic worthy of our discussion
それは私たちが議論する価値のある非常に大きなテーマです
like when I was studying in America
アメリカに留学していたときのように
Taiwan is so small
台湾はとても小さいです
more than 20 million people
兩千多萬人
Our overseas students who went to Taiwan are in the United States
台湾に行った留学生はアメリカにいます
belong to
に属する
It can't be said that it belongs to the number two, but also the number two and the number three.
ナンバー2に属するとは言えませんが、ナンバー2にもナンバー3にも属します。
we can see this
私たちはこれを見ることができます
is disproportionately much
不釣り合いに多い
even now
今でも
There is also mainland China ahead
その先には中国本土もある
there is india
インドがあります
but
しかし
Taiwan students
台湾の学生
Then we are also complaining
それなら私たちも文句言ってるよ
Young Malays do not study abroad
マレー人の若者は留学しない
what? What
何何
so comfortable these
とても快適です
but even so
しかしそれでも
Taiwan students
台湾の学生
Still in the top five
まだトップ5に入ってる
I'm in Taiwan for international students in the United States
私はアメリカの留学生のために台湾にいます
still so many
まだたくさん
So if we go and see
それで、行って見たら
once i did it
一度やりました
researching i found out that
調べて分かったのは
latin america
ラテンアメリカ
They are so close to America
彼らはアメリカにとても近いです
Do many of them choose America?
彼らの多くはアメリカを選びますか？
No
いいえ
you say middle east africa
中東アフリカって言うんですね
you look at the ratio
あなたは比率を見ます
Ratio to population
人口比
far inferior to Taiwan
台湾に比べればはるかに劣る
So our entire Taiwan
ですから私たち台湾全体が
and East Asia to the United States
そして東アジアから米国へ
relationship with the United States
米国との関係
very reflective
非常に反射的
our political dependence on him
私たちの彼への政治的依存
good
良い
But what I'm saying is this
しかし、私が言いたいのはこれです
That is to say, the role of the United States is very critical
つまり、米国の役割は非常に重要である
but
しかし
but we can't use dollars
でもドルは使えない
to explain Taiwan's success
台湾の成功を説明する
because
なぜなら
give two examples
2つの例を挙げてください
First
初め
in the mainland period
本土時代に
United States to the National Government
米国から中央政府へ
That's the one
それだ
The defeated America
負けたアメリカ
And the national government
そして、中央政府は、
also provided more assistance
さらなる支援も提供しました
but no good results
しかし良い結果は得られなかった
Then everyone in the rest of the world
それでは、残りの世界の皆さんも
Also many most cases
また、ほとんどの場合、
no good results
良い結果はありません
so it's critical
だからそれは重要だ
but can't explain
でも説明できない
But Taiwan is more fortunate
しかし台湾はもっと幸運だ
that's what i just said
それが私が今言ったことです
it has something to do with us
それは私たちに関係があります
one japan and one america
一つの日本と一つのアメリカ
It gave Taiwan a postwar
台湾に戦後をもたらした
Economically relatively self-developed space
経済的に比較的自己開発されたスペース
This is of course an arrangement for the Cold War layout.
もちろん、これは冷戦時代の配置のための取り決めである。
So the United States provides an umbrella for Taiwan
だから米国は台湾に傘を差し出す
market
市場
market is important
市場は重要です
we are at
私たちは〜にて
started in the 80s
80年代に始まった
we'll hear 3011 or something
3011か何かが聞こえます
But the first 30 years
でも最初の30年は
The United States is quite prosperous
アメリカはかなり裕福だ
open its door
そのドアを開けてください
Enter Taiwan's
台湾に入る
Export
輸出
no apology like it started in the 80s
80年代に始まったような謝罪はありません
At the same time, it is not in the market of Taiwan
同時に、台湾の市場にはありません
too small to be far from it
小さすぎてそこから遠く離れられない
but at the same time it was for cold war political reasons
しかしそれは同時に冷戦時代の政治的理由によるものでもあった
it tolerates the national government
それは国家政府を容認する
The industrialization of various developmental states
さまざまな発展状態の工業化
to protect the domestic market
国内市場を守るために
Supporting local industries and attracting foreign investment
地元産業の支援と海外投資の誘致
For example, all these actions are
たとえば、これらのアクションはすべて次のとおりです。
America in the late 80s
80年代後半のアメリカ
Start pushing the WTO
WTOへの働きかけを始める
don't do this don't do this
これをしないでくださいこれをしないでください
It's from East Asia
東アジアから来たものです
Four East Asian Tigers follow Japan's ICSID model
東アジアの4つのタイガーが日本のICSIDモデルを踏襲
Have you heard of the production review mode?
制作レビューモードについて聞いたことがありますか?
In fact, the Four East Asian Tigers are roughly
実際、東アジア四虎は大まかに次のとおりです。
Following Japan's ICSID model
日本のICSIDモデルを踏襲
For example, foreign capital came
例えば、外資が入ってきて、
just ask for it
ただそれを求めてください
You have to train local suppliers
地元のサプライヤーを訓練する必要がある
best for export
輸出に最適
Are you constantly increasing the proportion of local purchases
現地購入の割合を継続的に増やしていますか
All of these are now banned by the WTO
これらはすべて現在、WTOによって禁止されています
so of course it is
それは当然です
Taiwan is actually
実は台湾は
luckier in history
歴史上幸運だった
Of course, it was also due to the arrangement of the Cold War.
もちろん、それは冷戦の仕組によるものでもあった。
This is the opposite of what the US does in Latin America
これは米国がラテンアメリカで行っていることの逆である
For example, we know that Chile elected Ayed
たとえば、チリがアイド氏を選出したことはわかっています。
Ayed is not just a leftist
アイドは単なる左翼ではない
And he's going to resist the influence of American corporations
そして彼はアメリカ企業の影響に抵抗するつもりだ
He wants to nationalize the mines
彼は鉱山を国有化したいと考えている
Turns out we know he was overthrown in a coup and people were killed
彼がクーデターで打倒され、人々が殺されたことがわかっていることが判明した
At the same time the United States
同時にアメリカも
after World War II
第二次世界大戦後
In 1946, the Sino-US Treaty of Friendship, Commerce and Navigation was signed
1946年には中米友好通商航海条約が締結された。
China fully opens its door to the United States
中国が米国に全面的に門戸を開く
and only for the US
そして米国のみ
So it seems that the treaty seems to be still valid
どうやらこの条約はまだ有効のようだ
I met a friend who works in the media
メディア関係で働く友人に会いました
He said that now it seems that the movie imports something like this
彼は、今では映画がこのようなものを輸入しているようだと言いました
still citing the treaty
まだ条約を引用している
i don't know
わからない
I didn't check this part
この部分はチェックしていませんでした
So what I'm saying is this is the paradox
つまり、私が言いたいのは、これがパラドックスだということです
That is to say, it is the strategic consideration of the United States towards China.
つまり、米国の対中戦略的配慮である。
Make it highly tolerant of Taiwan's economic autonomy
台湾の経済的自主性に対して寛容になるようにする
Let's look at this more troublesome problem first.
まず、このさらに厄介な問題を見てみましょう。
It is how we view the role of the national government
国の役割をどう見るか
i mean to say
私が言いたいのは
We are in this process of democratization
私たちは民主化のプロセスの中にいます
because we want
私たちが欲しいから
that our society does
私たちの社会がそうしていること
successful
成功
relatively mild and peaceful approach
比較的穏やかで平和的なアプローチ
developed a discourse against authoritarian rule
権威主義的統治に反対する言説を展開した
This argument necessarily negates
この議論は必然的に否定する
deny many parts of him
彼の多くの部分を否定する
Variety
バラエティ
what i want to say is
私が言いたいのは
such a statement
そのような発言
It's what I just said
それは私が今言ったことです
Our current mainstream discourse
現在の主流の言説
his staged tasks
彼の段階的なタスク
should it come to an end
終わりが来るべきなのか
should we go
行きましょうか
to review the issue
問題を確認するには
I guess I'm not saying this argument is completely useless
この議論がまったく無駄だと言っているわけではないと思う
I'm not
私はそうではありません
i feel everything
私はすべてを感じます
Maybe we'll all have to look at it historically
おそらく私たち全員がそれを歴史的に見る必要があるでしょう
For example, I just mentioned
たとえば、先ほども言いましたが、
How do we view this mainstream discourse
この主流の言説をどう見るか
How to see the impact of Japanese colonial rule
日本の植民地支配の影響をどう見るか
If you want to deny the authoritarian rule of the national government
国家権力の強権支配を否定したいなら
Of course it's easy for you to deny everything about him
もちろん、彼についてすべてを否定するのは簡単です
Then say the Japanese are doing better than you
それなら日本人はあなたより上手いと言うよ
I just try to speak nice things about the Japanese
私はただ日本人について良いことを言おうとしているだけです
then say bad things about you
それからあなたのことを悪く言います
you can imagine this
これは想像できますね
This is an easy path
これは簡単な道です
but today
しかし今日は
Maybe we shouldn't take it so seriously
あまり真剣に受け止めるべきではないかもしれない
That way we'd better move on to the next step
そうすれば次のステップに進むことができます
what i want to say is
私が言いたいのは
In this mainstream discourse
この主流の言説では
will put the national government
中央政府を置くだろう
They just retreated and fled to Taiwan.
彼らはそのまま撤退して台湾に逃げた。
said to be a
であると言われています
outright alien regime
完全な外国人政権
a colonial regime
植民地政権
It's very convenient to say this
これを言うととても便利です
it's easy
それは簡単です
it's just really embarrassing to say it
それを言うのは本当に恥ずかしいです
easy to deny
否定するのは簡単
but it has its price
しかし、それには値段があります
Saying this has its price
これには代償があると言う
then i'm coming
それなら私は行きます
that is
あれは
colonial power is not a
植民地権力はそうではありません
freely definable
自由に定義可能
because it is a
それは
imperialist architecture
帝国主義建築
that is, you have to have colonists
つまり、入植者が必要です
you have the colonized
あなたは植民地化されたものを持っています
at the same time
同時
This colonization is for the benefit of the mother country
この植民地化は母国の利益のためです
and there should be differences in levels of development
発達レベルには差があるはずです
That is, the level of this home country is relatively high.
つまり、本国のレベルが比較的高いということです。
then it has the power to come
そうすれば、それは来る力を持っています
this
これ
to occupy this colony
この植民地を占領するために
Then let the benefit of this colony
それならこの植民地に利益をもたらしましょう
Serve home country
母国に奉仕する
this is a
これは
This one from the end of the 19th century
こちらは19世紀末のもの
an imperialist architecture
帝国主義的な建築
under that framework
その枠組みの下で
so we can talk about colonies
それで植民地について話しましょう
But treat the national government as a colonist
しかし中央政府を植民地人として扱う
raised it a bit too much
ちょっと上げすぎた
because it has no mother country
母国がないから
it is defeated
それは負けた
retreat to a very deep
非常に深いところまで後退する
one without governance
ガバナンスのないもの
It has only been governed for four years
統治されてからわずか4年しか経っていない
a god brought back
神が連れ戻された
In fact, when the National Government accepted the Northeast
実際、中央政府が東北地方を受け入れたとき、
also encountered similar trouble
私も同様のトラブルに遭遇しました
I guess it's the price of saying something like this
こういうことを言う代償なんだろうね
and then at the same time its level of development
そして同時にその開発レベル
Not particularly high compared to Taiwan
台湾に比べて特別高いわけではない
The point is not just saying
重要なのは単に言うことではありません
1. Once you describe the national government as a colonist
1. 中央政府を植民地主義者と表現したら
you don't
あなたはそうしない
no way to point to the real colonists
本当の入植者を指摘する方法はありません
Then you have no way to recognize our own place
そうなると、あなたは自分たちの場所を認識することができなくなります
you won't identify
あなたは特定しないでしょう
You will not point out that Japan was once our colonizer
日本がかつて我が国の植民地だったことは指摘しないだろう
then America to now
当時のアメリカから現在まで
still our important supporter
今でも私たちの大切なサポーターです
if you think about it
考えてみれば
It's true that we don't usually talk like this
確かに普段はこんな話しませんよね
we only hear
私たちは聞くだけです
The national government is a foreign regime and a colonial regime
国家政府は外国政権であり植民地政権である
we won't say what japan is like
日本がどんな国かは言いません
how is america
アメリカはどうですか
At the same time, there is no way to realize that
同時に、それを認識する方法はありません
When developing the economy in a backward country
後進国で経済を発展させる場合
its role in economic democracy
経済民主主義におけるその役割
this
これ
This way of thinking is different from what we have now
この考え方は今の考え方とは異なります
very relevant
非常に関連性の高い
Because our biggest difficulty now is how to get rid of
なぜなら、今の私たちの最大の困難は、それをどうやって取り除くかということだからです。
Facing mainland China
中国本土に面している
Then we are now the mainstream
それから今は私たちが主流です
is to continue the framework
枠組みを継続することです
the national government
中央政府
original enemy number one
本来の敵ナンバーワン
now enemy number one
今では敵第一位
to mainland China
中国本土へ
Also put it in a frame like this
こんなフレームにも入れてます
but the problem is
しかし問題は
This is for us to plan
これは私たちが計画するものです
our economic future
私たちの経済の未来
economic vision
経済ビジョン
only brings difficulties
困難をもたらすだけ
Because mainland China
中国本土だから
It also
また
In fact, the economic benefits to the present
実際、現時点での経済的利益は、
did not enter Taiwan
台湾に入国しなかった
its level of development
その開発レベル
not higher than Taiwan
台湾より高くない
It is Taiwan that is exporting capital
資本を輸出しているのは台湾です
manpower to the mainland
本土への人員派遣
so
それで
Such a structure allows us to understand
このような構造により、理解できるようになります。
National Government
中央政府
to understand
理解する
Now the number one enemy is mainland China
今や最大の敵は中国本土だ
are in the way
邪魔です
that's what i'm saying
まさにそれのこと
we have no way to go
私たちには行く道がない
If you face this problem
この問題に直面した場合
is the prospect of hindering our development
私たちの発展を妨げる可能性がある
well that
まあそれは
ok let's see
わかりました、見てみましょう
the national government
中央政府
After retreating to Taiwan in a disastrous defeat
大敗して台湾へ撤退後
doing
やってる
First he did a very important thing
まず彼はとても重要なことをした
land reform
土地改革
I enter
私が入ります
I also observed that in recent years
私も近年気づいたのですが、
There is a very
非常にあります
In line with this democratization
この民主化に合わせて
and such a statement
そしてそのような発言
there is a share
有一股
The voice is to deny land reform
土地改革を否定する声が大きい
That
それか
Or
また
Land reform is a foreign regime
土地改革は外国の政権だ
But the problem is the foreign regime
しかし問題は外国の政権だ
It is not necessary to do land reform, is it?
土地改革をする必要はないんじゃないでしょうか。
Japan Comes to Taiwan Although Tibetan Land Cancels Big Tenants
チベットランドが大規模テナントをキャンセルするも、日本が台湾に進出
But he didn't go further to do real land reform did he?
しかし、彼は本格的な土地改革には踏み込みませんでしたね。
So foreign regimes and land reform
外国の政権と土地改革
Foreign regimes may make land reform easier
外国政権が土地改革を容易にする可能性がある
But that doesn't mean he's going to
しかし、それは彼がそうするつもりであるという意味ではありません
This is of course the communist revolution in mainland China
これはもちろん中国本土の共産主義革命です
Under the Oppression of the Agrarian Revolution
農業革命の抑圧下で
Let those who had no determination to do this do it
これをやる決意のない人にやらせてください
But luckily with a compromise
しかし幸運にも妥協ができて
Even the landlords in Taiwan actually compromised
台湾の地主も実際に妥協した
did not rise up in rebellion
反乱を起こさなかった
So it's a three way compromise
つまり、三者択一の妥協案です
Land reform was carried out in a peaceful and stable manner
土地改革は平和的かつ安定的に行われた
Of course this is for Taiwan
もちろん台湾向けです
have a very important impact
非常に重要な影響を与える
because we see
私たちが見るから
Economic Development of COCO
COCOの経済発展
Hundreds of years
何百年も
it's a long process
それは長いプロセスです
So how do we describe this development?
では、この展開をどう説明すればいいでしょうか?
of course it is
もちろん
the french revolution
フランス革命
Britain's Glorious Revolution
イギリスの名誉革命
is what to do
何をすべきか
It is to overthrow the privileges of the feudal land aristocracy
それは封建的土地貴族の特権を打破することである
then let this
それならこれにしましょう
The rise of the bourgeoisie who wants to do business and industrialize
ビジネスと産業化を望むブルジョワジーの台頭
That
それか
Land Reform of the Nationalist Government
国民政府の土地改革
is a top-down
トップダウンです
Bourgeois revolution
ブルジョワ革命
then why would you do it
ではなぜそれをするのでしょうか
is led by the Communist Party of China
中国共産党が主導している
Under the pressure of the land revolution
土地革命の圧力の下で
Then it eliminates the left wing on the one hand
それから一方では左翼を排除する
It's 28 plus white terror
それは28プラス白色恐怖です
pardon his opposition
彼の反対を許してください
then under this pressure
それからこのプレッシャーの下で
he did
彼がやった
in order to maintain power
権力を維持するために
made some progress
もっと進歩的なことをした
including land reform
土地改革も含めて
ok so look at that
わかりました、それを見てください
this
これ
Did the Nationalist Government establish a monopoly in Taiwan after the war?
国民党政府は戦後、台湾に独占権を確立しましたか?
party-state capitalism
政党国家資本主義
Since 1991, Chen Simeng
1991 年以来、陳思夢
the six
6人
Facility Economist
施設エコノミスト
Wrote a book called Deconstructing Party-State Capitalism
『政党国家資本主義の解体』という本を執筆
is a very famous book
とても有名な本です
that he
彼が
It represents such a one of our economics
それは私たちの経済学のそのようなものを表しています
free market theory
自由市場理論
this democracy
この民主主義
To push is to overthrow authority
推進することは権威を転覆することである
with a nice combination
素敵な組み合わせで
so he was very successful
それで彼は大成功した
brought a term called party-state capitalism
政党国家資本主義という用語をもたらした
so from that
それでそこから
very successful
とても成功しました
Since then we have listened
それ以来、私たちは耳を傾けてきました
Just got the name
名前がついたばかりです
party-state capitalism
政党国家資本主義
but let's see
でも見てみましょう
Is it true? If all the KMT did was create a
それは本当ですか? もし国民党が行ったのが、
Monopoly
独占
The party-state capital
党と国家の首都
How can Taiwan still be able to develop?
どうして台湾はまだ発展できるのでしょうか？
that would be a real miracle
それは本当に奇跡だろう
That's actually
それは実際に
We can understand it by overcoming fear
恐怖を乗り越えれば理解できる
the national government
中央政府
So he received monopoly Japanese capital
そこで彼は独占的な日本の資本を受け取りました
Large enterprises remain state-owned but do not expand further
大企業は国有のままだが、それ以上拡大しない
Taiwan Sugar
台湾製糖
Taipower
タイパワー
CNPC what
CNPCって何？
Most of the emerging parts are open to the private sector
新興部分のほとんどは民間部門に開放されている
so
それで
so i'll wait
だから待ちます
show two pictures
2枚の写真を見せる
One is that in the 1950s, manufacturing and industry
1 つは、1950 年代に製造業と産業が
The proportion of private enterprises has exceeded half
民間企業の割合が半数を超えている
at the same time
同時
Taiwan's main private capital
台湾の主要な民間資本
are new post-war
戦後の新しいものです
This picture is very obvious
この写真は非常にわかりやすいです
This is it
これだよ
this is industry
これは業界です
1958 crossover
1958 クロスオーバー
So this private
それで、このプライベート
keep rising
上昇し続ける
The labor camp continued to decline
労働収容所は衰退し続けた
ok let's see
わかりました、見てみましょう
This is based on the Chinese Faith Institute
これは中国信仰研究所に基づいています
it came out in 2008
2008年に発売されました
Top 50 Group Enterprises in Taiwan
台湾のグループ企業上位50社
Then according to their founding years
その後、創業年に応じて
take a look
見てください
Only 5 are from before 1945
1945 年以前のものは 5 つだけ
It was very small before
以前はとても小さかったのですが
for example
例えば
For example, Big Companion
たとえば、ビッグコンパニオン
may be
多分
a small iron factory
小さな鉄工場
I think this mountain should be
この山はそうあるべきだと思う
There is also a telecommunications bureau
総合通信局もあります
Another one is Wan Hai
もう一人はワンハイです
Then the mainland came to Taiwan
そして大陸は台湾にやって来た
one is the same bureau
一つは同じ局です
Later changed its name to Yang Ming Shipping
その後陽明海運に社名変更
Because the mainland also has a bureau
本土にも局があるので
This was established during the Qing Dynasty
これは清の時代に確立されました。
The other is the Far East
もう一つは極東です
good
良い
So that is
つまり、
see is say
見ることは言うこと
Traditional industries in the 1950s and 1960s
1950年代から1960年代の伝統産業
and the financial industry
そして金融業界
Cathay Pacific Yuanshou
キャセイ元首
what starlight yuanshou
何のスターライト元祥
These are mainly domestic market
これらは主に国内市場です
traditional manufacturing and service industries
伝統的な製造業とサービス業
twenty
二十
Another big one is the high-tech industry
もう一つの大きな産業はハイテク産業です
Of course we know that he came after the 1970s
もちろん私たちは彼が 1970 年代以降に来たことを知っています
established
成立的
For example, like Shi Zhenrong, Lin Baili, Guo Taiming
たとえば、Shi Zhenrong、Lin Baili、Guo Taiming などです。
These are the postwar
これらは戦後です
He may not be born after the war
彼は戦後生まれではないかもしれない
but educated after the war
しかし教育を受けたのは戦後
Lin Baili once said
林百麗はかつてこう言った
National Taiwan University's Department of Electrical Engineering failed very badly
国立台湾大学電気工学科は大失敗
But let's look at their generation
しかし、彼らの世代を見てみましょう
His class is amazing
彼のクラスは素晴らしいです
He opened with his classmates
彼はクラスメートと話を始めた
so successful
とても成功しました
so i don't know if he is
だから彼がそうかどうかは分からない
what about his accusations
彼の告発はどうですか
we are hard to measure
私たちを測るのは難しい
so their generation
だから彼らの世代は
Taiwan's postwar-educated generation of engineers
台湾の戦後教育を受けた世代のエンジニア
Help Taiwan build high-tech
台湾のハイテク技術の構築を支援する
ok so this shows
OK、これでわかります
that's what i just said
それが私が今言ったことです
Taiwan's main private capital is post-war star
台湾の主要民間資本は戦後のスターだ
This is what I originally said
これは私が最初に言ったことです
Modern Industry in the Japanese Occupation Era
日本統治時代の近代産業
Mainly Japanese
主に日本人
and no japan
そして日本はない
did not train
トレーニングしませんでした
Cultivate local modern industry in Taiwan
台湾の地場近代産業を育成する
It's dependent
それは依存しています
At the same time he also shows
同時に彼は次のようにも示しています
After the fearful national government came to Taiwan
恐怖を克服した国民党政府が台湾に到着後
He is not like those authors say
彼はそれらの作家が言うような人ではありません
just means support
あくまでサポートという意味です
party-state capitalism
政党国家資本主義
ok let's look at this background
はい、背景を見てみましょう
good this
いいですね、これ
This is the KMT-CCP struggle, line competition
これは国民党と中国共産党の闘争、路線競争である
After the Kuomintang-Communist cooperation began on 1923 24
1923年に国民党と中国共産党の協力が始まってから24
Then they say
それから彼らは言います
2627 After the Purge
2627 粛清後
The Kuomintang and the Communist Party started like this
国民党と共産党はこうして始まった
a very tough competition
非常に厳しい競争
To seize the power to lead China's modernization
中国の近代化を主導する権力を掌握する
We know that the national government failed miserably
私たちは中央政府が惨めな失敗をしたことを知っています
Let's look at 1949
1949 年を見てみましょう
January 1949
1949年1月
Chen Cheng Street Audit Chairman
街頭裁判主席 陳成
At that time, the People's Liberation Army was preparing to cross the Yangtze River
当時、人民解放軍は長江渡河の準備をしていた。
just practice water combat first
まずは水上戦闘を練習してください
ship first
先要艦船
So at that time we can negotiate
その時は交渉してみようかな
There are eight conditions for peace talks
和平交渉には8つの条件がある
Land reform Confiscation of bureaucratic capital
土地改革 官僚資本の没収
Great Traitor Treaty
大裏切り者条約
The Mai Guo Treaty is the 1946 passage I just mentioned
マイグオ条約は、先ほど述べた 1946 年の条文です。
So when Chen Cheng took over Chairman God in January
それで、1月に陳成氏が神会長を引き継いだとき、
He said there's little to die for from here
ここからは死ぬことはほとんどない、と彼は言った
I think it can better show their mood at that time.
そのときの彼らの心情をより表現できると思います。
he did a lot that year
彼はその年たくさんのことをした
He immediately announced the implementation of the 375 inspection
彼はただちに375検査の実施を発表した。
no legal basis
法的根拠がない
he just does
彼はただそうするだけ
It is true that the construction started in the first quarter of the year
建設が今年の第 1 四半期に始まったのは事実です
I've never acted like this
私はこのような行動をしたことがありません
But Taiwan's conditions are better
しかし台湾の方が条件は良い
allow him to do this
彼にこれをやらせてください
Reform avoids wisdom
改革避智
Exchange Taiwan Dollars for New Taiwan Dollars
台湾ドルを新台湾ドルに両替
Then start setting up a committee to plan Home Rule
それから自治規則を計画するための委員会の設立を開始します
promulgate martial law
戒厳令を発布する
There will be an official signing at the end of the year
年末には正式なサイン会が行われる予定だ
finally reform party affairs
ついに党政を改革する
then white terror
それから白色テロ
Qing left wing
清左翼
ok then i
わかりました、それでは私は
Now I'm going to turn to this part of the economy
ここで経済のこの部分に目を向けます
At that time it was really stormy
あの時は本当に嵐でした
Economic crisis continues Hyperinflation
経済危機は続く ハイパーインフレ
fiscal deficit trade deficit
財政赤字 貿易赤字
Lack of foreign exchange Lack of supplies
外貨不足 物資不足
population and food pressure
人口と食糧圧力
Then I think everyone should
それならみんなもそうすべきだと思う
full of familiarity
親しみやすさに満ちた
One or two million people immigrated from the mainland
100万人か200万人が本土から移民した
population pressure food pressure
人口圧力 食糧圧力
Then
それから
Lack of money, lack of supplies, lack of foreign exchange
お金の不足、物資の不足、外貨の不足
Although a shipment of gold
ゴールドの発送ですが、
but
しかし
middle
中
just keep selling
ただ売り続けてください
You can see that its stock is constantly decreasing
在庫が減り続けているのがわかります
So this is very
それで、これはとても
It is indeed a state of economic crisis
まさに経済危機状態です
But we see that within two or three years
しかし、2、3 年以内にそうなることがわかります。
Indeed, these bureaucrats
まさに、この官僚たちは、
Ying Chongrong, Yan Jiagai, etc.
イン・チョンロン、ヤン・ジアガイなど
They did stabilize the situation
彼らは状況を安定させた
By 1952
1952年までに
Production returns to its highest level
生産は最高レベルに戻る
Prices start to stabilize
価格が安定し始める
at the same time
同時
Although the population has increased by one or two million
人口は100万も200万も増えているのに
However, food is generally stable
ただし、食料は概ね安定している
but i want to say
でも言いたい
Although the dollar plays an important role
ドルは重要な役割を果たしていますが、
but
しかし
not all
すべてではない
because you have dollars
あなたはドルを持っているから
like forty five to forty nine with dollars
ドルだと45から49くらい
you can mess up too
あなたも台無しにすることができます
It's also a mess on the mainland
本土も大混乱だよ
a mess, a fiasco
混乱、大失敗
The national government came to relatively small Taiwan
比較的小さな台湾に国民政府がやって来た
indeed overcome fear
確かに恐怖を克服する
those are capable
彼らは有能です
The financial bureaucrat came out ahead with his energy and job base
財務官僚はエネルギーと職盤で先を行った
to dominate economic affairs
経済情勢を支配できる
like pampering eye gel lids and more
贅沢なアイジェルのまぶたなど
ok then take a look
わかりました、それでは見てみましょう
The source of these talents
この才能の源は
get to know them
彼らと知り合う
their background
彼らの背景
their thoughts
彼らの考え
that is to say why am I talking
つまり、なぜ私が話しているのかということです
What about these talents?
これらの才能についてはどうですか？
It's because of the constant chaos at this time
現時点では常に混乱が続いているためです
At the same time we need to know
同時に私たちが知る必要があるのは、
The national government is indeed compared to the Japanese colonial government
まさに中央政府は日本の植民地政府に喩えられる
it is indeed a degree of modernization
それは確かにある程度の近代化である
Organization is relatively low
組織比較低
poor organizational skills
組織能力比較差
A government with a relatively weak system
比較的弱い制度を持つ政府
We can say a semi-modern government
半近代的な政府と言えます
So the role of these people is even more important
したがって、これらの人々の役割はさらに重要です
Thanks
ありがとう
Let's take a look at the resource committee
リソース委員会を見てみましょう
Because he is a cradle of talent
彼は才能の宝庫だから
It is the Tsinghua War in Japan
それは日本における清華戦争です
It is a very, very important event for China
中国にとって非常に重要な出来事だ
has its incredible effect
信じられないほどの効果があります
Around 1932
1932年頃
That is, 918 in Japan has already happened
つまり日本の918はすでに起きている
one or two years
1年か2年
then there is already
それならすでにあるよ
The situation of invading North China
華北侵攻の状況
So there was a saying at that time
その時にこんな言葉がありました
That is, the North China University of Finance and Economics can no longer fit a peaceful desk
つまり、華北財経大学にはもはや平穏なデスクは収まらないということだ。
that seems to be
それのようです
The student movement at that time was a famous saying
当時の学生運動の名言
So in 1932 the national government established the National Defense Design Committee
そこで 1932 年に政府は国防設計委員会を設立しました。
some hopeful intellectuals
一部の希望に満ちた知識人
in Beijing
北京で
Big intellectuals are also willing to start willing to join
大物知識人も積極的に参加し始めています
Then start teaching and inspecting minerals
その後、鉱物の指導と検査を開始します
what about
どうですか
In 1935, it was changed to the Resources Committee and the German
1935 年に、それは資源委員会とドイツの委員会に変更されました。
cooperation with nazi germany
ナチスドイツとの協力
then this
それからこれ
Ke Weilin
柯偉林
Wang Fu must be very familiar
王福はよく知っているに違いない
He is famous for speaking
彼は話すことで有名です
Cooperation between Nazi Germany and Chiang Kai-shek's Nationalist Government
ナチスドイツと蒋介石国民政府の協力
because after the war
なぜなら戦後
Germany lost any privileges of his imperialism
ドイツは帝国主義のあらゆる特権を失った
so he becomes a
それで彼は
non-imperialist advanced country
非帝国主義先進国
only
唯一的
So he is very willing to follow
だから彼はとても喜んでフォローしてくれる
Willing to help the Republic of China at that time
当時中華民国を助けるつもりだった
to build a military industry
軍事産業を構築する
what training
何のトレーニング
train the army like this
このように軍隊を訓練する
Just help me fight Japan in the future
将来日本と戦うのを手伝ってください
good
良い
it's really helpful
本当に役に立ちます
on fairly good terms
かなり良い条件で
He mainly goes to change some
彼は主にいくつかを変えるために行きます
this rare
この珍しい
metal
金属
During this two-person war
この二人の戦いの中で
is responsible for establishing
を確立する責任があります
we can see it was done in 1935
1935年に行われたことがわかります
Maybe Japan saw
もしかしたら日本も見たかもしれない
I think it's time to do it
やる時が来たと思う
I have no idea
何も思いつきません
1937 was like the Juqiao Incident
1937年は竹橋事件のようなものだった
so don't have much time to do too much
だからあまり多くのことをする時間はあまりない
Wartime MC is in the rear
戦時MCは後方にいます
build some industries
いくつかの産業を構築する
after america entered the war
アメリカが戦争に参戦した後
after pearl harbor
真珠湾の後
beauty is coming
美しさがやってくる
after that
その後
The committee can send someone to
委員会は誰かを次の場所に派遣することができます
The United States went to the commission
米国は委員会に行った
front and rear
前後
More than 500 people were sent
500名以上が派遣されました
so a very big person
だからとても大きな人です
very important thing
とても重要なこと
first batch
最初のバッチ
they formed
彼らは結成した
Later, the 31 Society was established
その後、31協会が設立されました
Because there are 31 people
31人もいるから
in may
5月
May 31
5月31日
Then it seems to have forgotten
それでは忘れてしまったようです
exist
存在
It seems to be May 31st
5月31日らしいです
set up their 3-one society
3-1社会を設立する
who does that include
それには誰が含まれますか
Shun Xuan
シュン・シュアン
Also including Wang An
ワン・アンも含めて
Later, Wang An Computer was established in the United States.
その後、米国にWang An Computerが設立されました。
Wang An
ワン・アン
Just this tiny tree
この小さな木だけ
Wang Anliu
王安柳
stay in america
アメリカに滞在する
Most of them returned to the mainland
彼らのほとんどは本土に戻った
So after they got to Pearl Harbor
それで彼らが真珠湾に到着した後
such training
そのようなトレーニング
helped China cultivate
中国の栽培を支援した
a lot of money
たくさんのお金
very important talent
非常に重要な才能
Then they simultaneously start doing
それから彼らは同時にやり始めます
economic planning
経済計画
Just after the war
戦後すぐ
what kind of industry are we going to build
どのような産業を築いていくのか
how to receive
受け取り方
what kind of new
どのような新しいものですか
What kind of new industry will be built, etc.
どのような新たな産業が構築されるのかなど。
very
とても
in their plans
彼らの計画では
There are two places that are very important
とても重要な場所が2つあります
One is of course the Northeast
一つはもちろん東北です
because
なぜなら
because this
なぜならこれは
in Japan
日本在
Because China was really poor at that time
当時の中国は本当に貧しかったので、
no industry
産業がない
this
これ
mostly in the northeast
主に東北にある
another piece
別の作品
in Taiwan
台湾で
good
良い
We know that there is a big problem with Northeast reception
東北地方の受信に大きな問題があることは承知しています
Russia
ロシア
japanese american what these
日系アメリカ人、これは何ですか
but
しかし
Taiwan's reception is very
台湾の歓迎度は非常に高い
very successful
非常地成功
at least voluntary committee
少なくとも任意委員会
with the Chief Executive's Office
最高経営責任者室と
Perfect teamwork
合作無間
received
受け取った
Relatively large
比較大的
enterprise
企業
voluntary committees in the national government
国の任意委員会
should be a better
より良いはずです
this piece
この作品
Emphasis on professional enterprise talent cultivation
プロフェッショナル企業の人材育成に重点を置く
Absorbed excellent science and engineering talents
理工系の優秀な人材を吸収
relatively sound system
比較的健全なシステム
Their
彼らの
Of course, the previous photo was talking to Chiang Kai-shek
もちろん、前の写真は蒋介石と話している写真です
Refuse the party's influence to enter
党の影響力の参入を拒否する
Don't send your CC pies what pies come in
入ってきたパイをCCに送らないでください
and successfully rejected
そして無事拒否されました
let it be a
それを
but also because of this
でもこれのせいでもある
The committee for
のための委員会
last so corrupt
最後はとても腐敗した
The soon-to-be-failing national government was particularly disappointed
まもなく崩壊するであろう中央政府は特に失望した
So the committee is
そこで委員会は、
The only unit that is not as good as the investment
投資ほど良くない唯一のユニット
so most people stay
だからほとんどの人が残る
stay on the mainland
本土に留まる
You say Li Guoding and Sun Yunxuan are
李国定と孫雲軒はそうだと言うね
Are you here to vote for Taiwan?
台湾に投票しに来ましたか？
no they are
いいえ、彼らはそうです
sent earlier
先に送信されました
Taiwan to receive Taiwan
台湾が台湾を受け入れる
good so
いいですね
The capital committee came to receive
資金委員会が受け取りに来ました
Top 10 companies established by Japanese-funded enterprises
日系企業が設立した企業トップ10
their reception is better
彼らの受信状態は良好です
it is a pity
それは残念だ
The national government will not send them to receive
国は彼らを受け取りに送りません
Research Commons
研究公賣局
Otherwise, there shouldn't be such a mess
そうでなければこんな混乱は起こらないはず
So it's better for them to receive more productive grades
したがって、より生産的な成績を獲得したほうが良いのです
After
後
These large-scale talents of the Self-committee are the cross-strait
自主委員会のこれらの大型人材は台湾海峡の両側の人々です
At the same time, it is the foundation of state-owned enterprises on both sides of the strait
同時に、それは海峡の両側の国有企業の基盤でもあります。
so
それで
So if we look at
それで見てみると
Older state-owned enterprises in the mainland
本土の古い国有企業
Compared with the old public enterprises in Taiwan
台湾の旧公営企業との比較
you see a lot of similarities
類似点がたくさんありますね
When everyone is driving, go to refuel
みんなが運転してたら給油しに行く
please pay attention
注目してください
Medium oil
中油
CNPC doesn't have a logo
CNPCにはロゴがありません
there is a word below
下に言葉があります
That's the word committee
それは委員会という言葉です
Okay, so after the war in Taiwan
さて、台湾では戦後、
Eight of the top 15 economic ministers
上位15人の経済大臣のうち8人が
from self-committee
自己委員会から
Rong Li Guoding in the movie
映画の栄李国定
Sun Yuxuan
孫玉軒
Zhao Yaodong
趙耀東
Li Danghai and so on
李丹海など
good
良い
Then I will be honored in the movie
そうすれば映画で光栄に思うよ
As an example
例として
Come
来て
speaking of this generation
この世代と言えば
then i say this
それから私はこう言います
not to
しない
what kind of personality cult
どのような個人崇拝ですか
or what kind of meaning
あるいはどのような意味があるのか
but to explain
しかし説明するには
in this way
この上
a historical background
歴史的背景
to explain
説明する
Against such a historical background
このような歴史的背景から
this group of people
この人々のグループ
Have such a great sense of mission
とても大きな使命感を持っています
to help Taiwan
台湾を助けるために
in that chaos
その混乱の中で
Laid the foundation for future development
将来の発展のための基礎を築いた
good
良い
then I will start with
それでは始めます
so here's what i'm saying
だからここで私が言いたいのは
that is
あれは
In addition to ability
能力に加えて
ability
能力
Of course it's important
もちろんそれは重要です
work performance
仕事のパフォーマンス
there is a crisis
危機があります
they can handle
彼らは対処できる
in mainland period
本土時代に
This kind of people fight lightly
こういう人は軽く戦う
yes of course
はい、もちろん
always serious
いつも真剣な
So those who are capable may not be able to stand out
だから、できる人は目立たないかもしれない
but in the last days
しかし最後の日には
This heightened sense of crisis
この危機感の高まり
make the ruler
定規を作る
willing
喜んで
or he feels he must
あるいはそうしなければならないと感じている
to those who can
できる人たちへ
right
右
I take the exempt occupation as an example
免除される職業を例に挙げます
I just want to use this to illustrate
これを説明するために使用したいだけです
Will to develop
発展する意志
1951 to 53
1951年から53年
There is a program called
というプログラムがあります
To be visited
訪問予定
can be complicated to explain
説明が複雑になることがある
but in simple terms
しかし、簡単に言えば
imitation means
模倣という意味
government takes care of everything
政府がすべてを処理します
took American cotton
アメリカ綿を採用した
Giving room battlefield
部屋を与える戦場
It's like giving you a sum
金額を渡すようなものです
OEM money
OEMのお金
Then after the room is sandy
そして部屋が砂だらけになったら
back to the government
政府に戻る
The government put the housing good sand
政府は住宅に良い砂を入れた
Take it to the branch factory
支店工場に持って行きます
then pay another
その後、別の支払い
branch fee
支部費
then back again
それからまた戻ってきます
Then the cloth that was brought back
そして持ち帰った布は
Then give the marketing system
次に、マーケティングシステムを提供します
resend
再送信する
So it's called generation imitation generation branch
だからそれは世代模倣世代分岐と呼ばれます
highly dominant
非常に支配的な
this
これ
The choice of the man in the movie was at that time
映画の男の選択はその時だった
he said it was
彼はそうだと言った
war time
戦時中
war economy
戦争経済
then the mainland
それから本土
Chitai
千台
Mainland China
大陸千台
This one from Shanghai Qiantai
こちらは上海銭台産
Fangsadin
ファンサディン
has come
来た
how many million
何百万
this is already existing
これはすでに存在しています
then i will
それなら私がします
give priority to supporting them
彼らをサポートすることを優先する
because
なぜなら
yes no more
はい、もうだめです
Use foreign exchange to buy Dingding, Dingding, etc.
外国為替を使用して、ディンディン、ディンディンなどを購入します。
Therefore, the priority is to support the mainland to lead Taiwan to visit the killing field
したがって、台湾が殺害現場を訪問するよう本土を支援することが優先である。
Then so now imagine this
それでは、今、これを想像してください
How much controversy can be caused
どれだけの論争を巻き起こすことができるか
but he did
しかし彼はそうしました
So when he was visiting the capital
それで彼が首都を訪れていたとき、
made a high degree of trade-off
高度なトレードオフを行った
made a lot of decisions
たくさんの決断を下した
and then there are highly criticized
そしてその後、非常に批判される
For example, like Lei Zhen's Free China
たとえば、雷振氏の自由中国のような
I also saw articles criticizing him
彼を批判する記事も見た
then say
それから言う
because we can imagine saying
こう言うのが想像できるからです
how much trouble can happen
どれだけのトラブルが起こり得るか
That's the one someone secretly sold
あれは誰かが密かに売っていたものです
Somebody profited from it, what, what, what
誰かがそれで利益を得た、何、何、何
At the same time, give priority to supporting the leading Taiwan in the mainland
同時に、大陸で主導権を握る台湾への支援を優先する。
visit killing field
訪殺場
There are also articles criticizing Free China
自由中国を批判する記事もある
How can Taiwan have such a scale to develop imitation teacher industry
台湾はどうしてこれほどの規模で模倣教師産業を発展させることができるのでしょうか？
might as well import
輸入してもいいかもしれない
So on that example
その例では
I think Free China may not be right
自由中国は正しくないかもしれないと思う
but it's messy
でも汚い
But in the summer of 1953
しかし1953年の夏、
succeeded two years later
2年後に成功した
achieved autonomy
自律性を達成した
at the same time
同時
Wu Zhongrong immediately announced the end of this Program
呉忠栄氏は直ちにこのプログラムの終了を発表した
That is to say, for these
つまり、これらにとっては、
It turns out that he fostered the support of the object
彼がオブジェクトのサポートを促進したことが判明
he tested
彼はテストした
At the same time, gradually open up new manufacturers to enter
同時に新規メーカーの参入も徐々に開拓
promote market competition
市場競争を促進する
Slowly Tainan Bang also came in
ゆっくりとタイナンバンも入ってきました
what wait
何を待ってください
So four years later
それで4年後
is completely open
完全にオープンです
he used to have
彼はかつて持っていた
During this process
このプロセス中に
he once said
彼はかつて言った
The factory is not ready yet
工場はまだ準備ができていません
written agreement
書面による同意
The product is not yet in large quantities literally
この製品は文字通りまだ大量に供給されていません
The request to restrict the establishment of factories has been put forward
工場立地の制限要請が出されました
so
それで
So it means that in this process
つまり、このプロセスでは
individual
個別
Manufacturers are constantly asking
メーカーは常に質問しています
Your protection of me continues
あなたが私を守ってくれ続ける
so
それで
no matter what
何があっても
I this this is all kinds of protection
これはあらゆる種類の保護です
but he ended up
しかし彼は結局終わった
open all
すべて開く
So what I'm saying is that he set up various individual interest requirements
つまり、私が言いたいのは、彼はさまざまな個人の利益要件を設定したということです
petition basis for dating
デートの申し立ての根拠
The benefits of overall long-term development come in the form of
全体的な長期開発の利点は次のような形で現れます。
of course
もちろん
Offended a lot of people in the process
その過程で多くの人を怒らせた
good
良い
Let me continue with the example
例を続けてみましょう
it was in 1951
それは1951年のことでした
it said a famous saying
有名な言葉を言いました
Imported cloth is not as good as imported yarn
輸入布は輸入糸ほど良くない
Imported yarn is not as good as imported flowers
輸入糸は輸入花ほど良くない
put down cotton juice
綿汁を垂らします
It is not as good as upstream and downstream to develop together
上流と下流が一緒に開発するのは良くない
It is cotton and then put raw yarn
綿花に生糸を入れます
Yarn sausage is a relatively capital-intensive
糸ソーセージは比較的資本集約的です
this production activity
この生産活動
and then after yarn
そして糸の後
then there is branch cloth
それから布があります
Cloth
布
Although at that time
当時ですが
Of course, it is all powered by cloth
もちろんすべて布の力で作られています
But it can be smaller
でももっと小さくてもいいよ
So yarn sausage and cloth sausage are separated
糸ソーセージと布ソーセージが分かれているので
That is to say
つまり
They are upstream and downstream
それらは上流と下流にあります
interests between them
彼らの間の利益
there will be conflict
衝突が起こるだろう
good
良い
So it has to develop a set of
したがって、次のセットを開発する必要があります。
To reconcile the interests of upstream and downstream
上流と下流の利害を調整する
So it is giving upstream
つまり上流に与えるのです
Sasa
ササ
While providing trade protection
貿易保護を提供しながら
it for it
それのために
Its price, quality and protection period are limited
価格、品質、保護期間が限られている
that is
あれは
good
良い
you can act like a fool
あなたは愚か者のように振る舞うことができます
Then I'll give you two or three years of protection
そうすれば2、3年の保護を与えます
Protection means I restrict imports
保護とは輸入を制限することを意味します
But your quality must meet the downstream needs
ただし、品質は下流のニーズを満たさなければなりません
branch factory needs
支社工場のニーズ
At the same time your price cannot exceed
同時に、価格を超えることはできません
25% of the import price
輸入価格の25％
for example
例えば
So you see this is a
これは
I study economic development
私は経済発展について研究しています
I think it's a very important
とても重要なことだと思います
institutional innovation
制度的革新
its protection is conditional
その保護は条件付きです
There is a deadline
期限があります
i just said
私はちょうど言いました
that is two or three years
それは2年か3年です
Then your price cannot exceed
そうすればあなたの価格はそれを超えることはできません
How much is the international price
国際価格はいくらですか
Then your quality should be in a reasonable range
そうすれば、品質は妥当な範囲内になるはずです
Can't say that downstream comes to quarrel with me every day
下流が毎日喧嘩しに来るとは言えない
say your disagreement
あなたの意見の相違を言ってください
But if you're in the range
でも範囲内にいるなら
if possible
もし可能なら
Downstream must endure for two years
下流は2年間耐えなければならない
so this is a set
これはセットです
what say this is
これは何と言うか
An innovation made by Taiwan
台湾が生んだイノベーション
Of course, South Korea also imitated this later.
もちろん、後に韓国もこれを真似しました。
So this is the East Asian model
これが東アジアモデルです
The key to outperforming Latin America
ラテンアメリカを上回るパフォーマンスを発揮するための鍵
It means that the protection is limited and conditional
保護が限定的かつ条件付きであることを意味します
You didn't protect your childish industry and couldn't grow up
幼稚な業界を守らなかったので成長できなかった
But if your protection lasts
しかし、もしあなたの保護が続くなら
it doesn't grow
成長しない
so this is
それでこれは
that time in difficult times
困難な時代のあの時
it is based on actual needs
それは実際のニーズに基づいています
solve this problem
この問題を解決します
It's not signing money
お金にサインするわけではない
But it really wants to solve the problem
しかし、本当に問題を解決したいのです
so they don't stop it
だから彼らはそれを止めない
they figured out this way
彼らはこのように考え出した
Later also legislated
その後法制化もされた
there is such a law
そのような法律があります
So its principals have a clear vision for development
そのため、担当者は明確な開発ビジョンを持っています。
is to make Taiwan
台湾を作ることです
Complete the great cause of establishing a modern industrial production system
近代工業生産システム確立の大義を完遂する
so he has a clear vision
だから彼は明確なビジョンを持っている
Therefore, except in the 500th generation, he
したがって、500 世代を除いて、彼は
In addition to the development of tied branches and leaves in the way of integration from top to bottom
枝葉を結んで上から下まで一体化した展開に加え、
He also started to promote the original fiber in the 500 generation
500世代からオリジナルファイバーの普及にも着手
Do we grow up in Taiwan and feel that it should be like this?
台湾で育った私たちは、台湾はこうあるべきだと感じるでしょうか？
what's the big deal
何が大したことですか
Isn't that the way things should be?
それが物事のあるべき姿ではないでしょうか？
But if we look at other backward countries
しかし他の後進国を見てみると
We found out that except for South Korea
韓国を除いて
no other country does this
こんなことをする国は他にない
That is, other countries use US dollars to import and kill
つまり、他の国は米ドルを使って輸入し、殺しているということです。
or imported cloth
または輸入布
Unlike Taiwan and South Korea
台湾や韓国と違って
cotton is imported in US dollars
綿花は米ドルで輸入されています
like pakistan and india
パキスタンやインドのように
they produce their own good
彼らは自分たちの良いものを生み出します
They have also developed a non-visit industry
非訪問産業も発展させた
But after the development, they are busy fighting each other.
しかし、それが終わると、彼らはお互いに戦うのに忙しいです。
So there is no further development
よってこれ以上の発展は無い
not like Taiwan
台湾らしくない
Because of the development of exemption from visits, the development of rash
訪問免除の展開により、発疹が発症
Dr. Chen, then Immortal, then Mixed Defense, etc.
チェン博士、次に不滅、次に混合防御など。
all the way down
ずっと下まで
So like now we have many
だから今のように私たちにはたくさんの
like plastic bottles or something
ペットボトルか何かのように
Those are the original raw materials
それらがオリジナルの原材料です
This is the Coliac
これがコリアック病です
what these started making plastic bottles
ペットボトルを作り始めたきっかけ
It's moved downstream
下流に移動しました
upstream and start doing something else
上流で何か他のことを始めてください
So Taiwan actually relies on this business of visiting
つまり、台湾は実際にこの訪問ビジネスに依存しているのです。
long meal
長い食事
moggy in wollin soon
もうすぐウォリンのモギー
Taiwan is indeed a small market
台湾は確かに小さな市場です
There is a surplus of non-visit business
非訪問業務が余っている
So 1960 had this
1960年にはこれがありました
famous policy turn
有名な政策転換
From import substitution to export subsidies
輸入代替から輸出補助金へ
Since then, Taiwan has entered into a rapidly growing export-led growth
それ以来、台湾は輸出主導型の急速な成長を遂げました。
Okay, so what I'm trying to emphasize here is that
さて、私がここで強調したいのは、
The concept and practice of this set of industrial policies after the war is a kind of institutional innovation
戦後のこの一連の産業政策の構想と実践は、一種の制度革新である。
it's from them
それは彼らからです
At that time, I worked very hard to solve the crisis and difficulties at that time.
当時、私はその危機と困難を解決するために一生懸命働きました。
Then this set of practices laid the foundation for Taiwan's economic construction policy in the decades after the war
その後、この一連の実践が戦後数十年間の台湾の経済建設政策の基礎を築きました。
That is, our entire economy later
つまり、後で私たちの経済全体が
Later these
後でこれら
The Beauty Association, the Work Committee, the Economic and Security Council are all merged into the Ministry of Economic Affairs
美容協会、労働委員会、経済安全保障評議会はすべて経済省に統合される
Then a part goes to the Ministry of Economic Affairs
それから一部は経済省に行きます
Then the predecessor of the Economic Association was established
その後、経済協会の前身が設立されました。
Then this system continues to the present
その後この制度は現在まで続いています
Of course it's very different now
もちろん今は全く違います
ok let me say it again
わかりました、もう一度言わせてください
background of movie glory
映画の中でのロンインの背景
that's what he's going to do
それが彼がやろうとしていることだ
Of course it will cost a lot
もちろん費用もかなりかかりますが
That is to say, I have just emphasized
つまり、先ほど強調したのは、
That is to say, the national government at that time
つまり、当時の国家政府は、
yes it's still confusing
はい、まだ混乱しています
This system is not perfect
システムの調子が悪い
The organization is not perfect
組織は完璧ではありません
Then we Chinese are very good at putting pressure on each other
それから、私たち中国人はお互いにプレッシャーをかけるのがとても上手です
Guan Qiang's light pressure is happy once
関強の軽い圧力は一度幸せです
So Ying Zhongrong's style
蘇英中栄のスタイル
Of course I made a lot of enemies
もちろん敵もたくさん作りました
So he was accused in 1955
それで彼は1955年に告発された
Talking about the Yang Zimu financial case to benefit others
他の人のためにヤン・ジムーの経済事件について話す
dismissed from office
役職から解任された
Then apparently he offended his officer too
それからどうやら彼は警官も怒らせたらしい
So he didn't protect him
したがって彼を守らなかった
So he was dismissed for two years
それで彼は2年間解雇された
but paid
しかし支払われた
He still maintains his style
彼は今でも自分のスタイルを維持している
is the courage to recognize
認識する勇気です
then take
それなら両方とも取る
make very high-risk decisions
非常にリスクの高い決断を下す
Then he was in 1953
それから彼は1953年に
when writing a letter to a friend
友達に手紙を書くとき
Talking about the country's crisis, I was born at the age of 50
国の危機について語る、私は50歳で生まれた
as long as you can work hard
頑張れる限りは
another ten years
あと10年
Even death is not courageous
死ぬことすら勇気じゃない
also with Cheng Chan
チェン・チャンとも
He did write this after
彼はその後これを書きました
died ten years ago
10年前に亡くなりました
Then he spent his life
それから彼は生涯を終えた
Guo Songtao
郭松濤自曠
Guo Songtao was in the late Qing Dynasty
郭松濤は清朝末期の人物。
The Westernized National Salvation Faction in the Xianghuai Army
翔淮軍の西洋化救国派
Ambassador to the UK
駐英国大使
wrote Jicheng
ジチェンは書いた。
It is recommended to adopt the Western system
西洋のシステムを採用することをお勧めします
then be infinite
そうすれば無限になる
dismissed from office and died in depression
うつ病になるまで会社を解雇される
So this is his example
これが彼の例です
but
しかし
but also his
しかし、彼の
lessons learned
学んだ教訓
Because Guo Songtao is not a good person
郭松濤は良い人ではないので
after dismissal
解雇後
Cursed his enemies in private
プライベートで敵を呪った
so difficult to recover
回復するのがとても難しい
So this Wu Zhongrong is
つまり、この呉忠栄は
Being scolded off, being scolded all day or being scolded
怒られる、一日中怒られる、怒られる
He doesn't scold anyone in private
彼はプライベートでは誰も叱らない
So someone guessed
それで誰かが推測した
On the one hand, he takes Guo Zhongyou as an example
一方で、彼は郭仲佑を例に挙げています。
On the one hand, it is also a lesson from others
一方で、それは他人からの教訓でもあります
Don't scold others in private, don't scold even one enemy
人前で他人を叱るな、一人の敵でも叱るな
sure enough
案の定
From 1957 to 63 years after his death
1957年から彼の死後63年まで
he served five years
彼は5年間服役した
Indeed he has many enemies
確かに彼には多くの敵がいる
After his death there was talk of an attack
彼の死後、襲撃の話があった
some people objected
何人かの人々は反対した
Some entrepreneurs say
一部の起業家は言う
We're going to start a foundation to raise money for him.
私たちは彼のために資金を集めるための財団を設立するつもりです。
Someone rushed over and tore off the fundraising cloth
誰かが駆け寄って募金活動用の布を引き剥がした
so he does have his enemies
だから彼には敵がいる
well that
まあそれは
but i take
でも私は取る
example in the movie
映画の中の例
but
しかし
There are many other forces in the same period
同時期には他にも多くの勢力が存在する
That is, let's see him write this letter
つまり、彼がこの手紙を書くのを見てみましょう
it's for his friends
それは彼の友達のためです
They are of the same generation
彼らは同世代です
the same feelings
同じ感情
they think we should
彼らは私たちがそうすべきだと考えています
do something like this
このようなことをしてください
so
それで
We must start from the background of this generation
私たちはこの世代の背景から始めなければなりません
to understand
理解する
So I call them
だから私は彼らに電話します
An official who serves the country through industry
産業を通じて国に奉仕する役人
instead of
それ以外の
what we understand now
私たちが今理解していること
They seem to be more moral financial bureaucrats
彼らはより道徳的な財務官僚のようだ
I think
私が思うに
It doesn't seem like this
そうではないようです
cannot fully represent their
彼らのことを完全に表現することはできない
this state
この状態
I
私
here is a big
ここに大きなものがあります
There are some
幾つかある
the case
ケース
like what would he do
彼はどうするだろうか
high risk things
リスクの高いもの
For example once
たとえば一度
A batch of imported materials
輸入された材料のバッチ
Single brother due to tax dispute
税金争いのため独身の兄弟
To keep these materials from rotting
これらの材料を腐らせないようにするには
Take the initiative to provide guarantees by the CITIC Bureau
CITIC事務局が率先して保証を提供します
Then he repeatedly decided to get a loan from the CITIC Bureau
その後、彼は何度も中信局から融資を受けることを決意した。
For private enterprises in financial difficulties
経営難に陥った民間企業のために
poplar wood
ポプラの木
Then, for example, he disregarded the opposition of the army
そして、例えば、彼は軍の反対を無視した
Ritsu manufactures military shoes with Shinsan leather
リツはシンサンレザーで軍靴を製造
Develop leather industry
皮革産業の発展
Against the objections of the Bureau of Zero Objects
ゼロオブジェクト局の反対に対して
Import Liuwan, develop the deck industry, etc.
六湾の輸入、デッキ産業の発展など。
so he
彼は
He has the courage to make enemies and this cut
彼は敵を作る勇気を持っている、そしてこのカット
we'll now feel like saying
私たちは今こう言いたくなります
This kind of decision-making that seems to have the risk of benefiting others
このような他者を利するリスクを伴う意思決定
and he
そして彼
that is
あれは
after dismissal
解雇後
he still maintains
彼は今でもこう主張している
such style
そんなスタイル
ok then i should close it soon
わかりました、すぐに閉めましょう
so i just said
だから私はちょうど言った
I'm not trying to make it into a cult individual
カルト集団に仕立て上げるつもりはない
is not what it means
それが意味するものではありません
Rather, it must be under the background of that era
むしろ、そういう時代背景があったのでしょうね
Let them be a little reckless and do these things
少し無謀になってこんなことをさせてください
their sense of mission
彼らの使命感
Then that environment also needs such a person
じゃあその環境にもそういう人が必要だ
Only in the absence of system and lack of organization
システムや組織が欠如している場合にのみ
then an economy
それから経済
Economically chaotic situation to solve the problem
経済的に混乱した状況を解決するには
and then fix the problem
そして問題を解決してください
in the process of problem solving
問題解決の過程で
Founded Taiwan
台湾を建国
foundation of economic development
経済発展の基礎
so
それで
So the process is very dependent on
したがって、プロセスは以下に大きく依存します
motivation of these people
この人たちのモチベーション
And then I'm going to talk about their motivation
それから彼らの動機について話します
originate from
に由来する
Inheritance of the Old Wang Tucheng of Chinese Intellectuals
中国知識人の王土成老の継承
and during the KMT-CCP struggle
そして国民党と中国共産党の闘争中
By the National Government
中央政府による
their disastrous experience
彼らの悲惨な経験
and because they were
そして彼らはそうだったので
Defeated by the revolution of the Communist Party of China
中国共産党革命により敗北
so they borrow sex fear
だから彼らは性的恐怖を借用する
purge the left
左翼を粛清する
white terror very bloody
白色テロ非常に血なまぐさい
but on the other hand
しかし一方で
Also use the fear of sex to follow the Three People's Principles
セックスの恐怖も利用して三民主義を守る
The development model of military endowment
軍備の発展モデル
At the same time, due to land reform
同時に、土地改革により、
this china
この中国
The Land Reform of the Communist Party of China The Success of the Land Revolution
中国共産党の土地改革 土地革命の成功
made them attach great importance to agriculture
彼らに農業を非常に重視させた
So throughout the 1950s and 1960s
つまり、1950 年代から 1960 年代にかけて
sixty
六十
Mainly the 1950s for agriculture
主に1950年代の農業用
is very important
はとても重要です
part of agriculture
農業の一部
Agricultural Restoration
農業の復興
The Peasant Rehabilitation Conference is also ours
農民更生会議も私たちのものです
tell a similar story
似たような話をする
but of course he has his price
しかしもちろん彼には代償がある
just cleared the left wing
左翼を通過したところです
So this is the disappearance of the left eye
つまり、これは左目の消失です
This is Chen Yingzhen
チェン・インジェンです
is our famous writer
私たちの有名な作家です
his terms
他的用語
that is to say he said
つまり彼は言った
Taiwan is a society where the left eye does not disappear
台湾は左目が消えない社会
The left eye may not be very important
左目はあまり重要ではないかもしれない
But your lack of a left eye is an imbalance
でも君の左目が欠けているのはバランスが崩れている
ok so i gave them a name
さて、名前を付けました
They are not just economic bureaucrats
彼らはただの経済官僚ではない
It is the traditional intellectuals who save the country with industry and save the nation.
産業で国を救い、国家を救うのは伝統的な知識人です。
Finally, let me talk about the hardworking people
最後に、勤勉な人々について話しましょう
because i didn't just say
ただ言ったわけじゃないから
In our mainstream discourse, there are three
私たちの主流の議論には3つあります
Either Japan or the United States or the people
日本か米国か国民か
but of course our people work hard
しかし、もちろん私たちの従業員は一生懸命働いています
We are still working hard
私たちはまだ頑張っています
Look we are now 8:30
ほら、もう8時半だよ
still doing it here, isn't it?
まだここでやってるんですよね？
Taiwan's working hours have been among the longest in the world
台湾の労働時間は世界最長の部類に入る
Out at the top
トップに出て
It seems that South Korea is number one compared to us and is second
私たちと比較すると韓国が1位で2位のようです
The focus is on the development of backward countries
後進国の発展に焦点を当てる
Not because, mainly not because their people don't work hard
それは主に彼らの人々が一生懸命働いていないからではありません
You said that China has been
あなたは中国がそうなったと言いました
Did the people not work hard before?
人々は以前は一生懸命働いていませんでしたか？
So I guess it shouldn't be a main explanatory variable
したがって、それは主要な説明変数であってはいけないと思います
I am emphasizing here the role of economic bureaucrats
私はここで経済官僚の役割を強調しています。
i now go back to the whole noun
ここで名詞全体に戻ります
It is because the economic development of backward countries requires good economic policies
後進国の経済発展には優れた経済政策が必要だからです
Because you are behind, you have to catch up
遅れているから追いつかないといけない
You used to be from a traditional agricultural society
あなたは伝統的な農業社会の出身でした
What was your original system?
元々のシステムは何でしたか？
For the imperial examination, you have to write eight-legged essays
科挙では八本足の論文を書かなければなりません
then what
じゃあ何
For entering an industrial society
産業社会への参入に向けて
Of course not well prepared
もちろん準備も整っていない
next to you is facing
あなたの隣が向いている
Very advanced productivity in Europe, America and Japan
ヨーロッパ、アメリカ、日本における非常に高い生産性
you have to do
あなたがしなければなりません
You certainly need the government to play a very important role
確かに政府が非常に重要な役割を果たす必要がある
So the more backward the role of the government is, the more important it is
したがって、政府の役割が後進的であればあるほど、その重要性は増します。
So it's not that the people don't work hard
だから国民が頑張らないわけではない
It's not that people don't matter
人が関係ないわけではない
but you fall behind
でもあなたは遅れます
The more you need a focus
集中力が必要なほど
collective power
集合力
to solve the problem
この問題を解決するために
Japanese Occupation Period
日本統治時代
Of course the Japanese colonial government
もちろん日本植民地政府も
is a relatively modern
比較的現代的なものです
More Advanced Governance Organization
より高度なガバナンス組織
but
しかし
But the Japanese colonial government
しかし、日本の植民地政府は、
not willing
やる気がない
its will is to develop
その意志は発展することです
the economy of their home country
母国の経済
it has no will
それには意志がない
no will to develop
発展する意志がない
local power
地元の力
So the Japanese occupation period
つまり日本統治時代は
Although the foundation was laid
基礎はできたものの、
established the system
システムを確立しました
But it suppresses the local
しかし、それは地元の人々を抑制します
economic vitality
経済活力
After the environment is suitable
環境が整ってから
will be able to play
遊べるようになるでしょう
Just like the coastal areas after China's reform and opening up
まるで中国の改革開放後の沿岸部のようだ
Simultaneous Japanese Occupation Period
同時日本占領時代
limited higher education
限られた高等教育
Keep an eye out for talent in an era dominated by America
アメリカ主導の時代の才能に注目
Difficult to play
遊びにくい
make the contradiction more prominent
矛盾をさらに目立つようにする
But in fact
しかし実際には
Authoritarian repression knows no provinces
権威主義的弾圧は地方を知らない
Because the asset management committee invests in the mainland
資産管理委員会が本土に投資しているため
So the resources will be in Taiwan
つまりリソー​​スは台湾にあります
Although the role of these people is very important
これらの人々の役割は非常に重要ですが、
But I believe that you may not have heard of
しかし、あなたは聞いたことがないかもしれないと思います
Because as a ministerial unit
なぜなら省庁単位として
He voted collectively
彼はまとめて投票した
The first step of the national government is to kill chickens and enter the marquis
国家政府の第一歩は鶏を殺して侯爵家に入る事だ
after they voted
彼らが投票した後
Compare Taitang with Taipower
タイタンとタイパワーの比較
Dr. Liu MeiGeneral Manager
Dr. Liu Meiゼネラルマネージャー
out of death
死からの脱出
Espionage case
匪諜案
After the Chicken Killer enters the Marquis
チキンキラーが侯爵入りした後
After killing chickens and entering Hou, the capital committee was reorganized
鶏を殺して侯に入った後、首都委員会が再組織された
But these talents are still necessary
しかし、これらの才能は依然として必要です
So use it
だからそれを使ってください
So this becomes a less
したがって、これは少なくなります
Frequently Discussed Topics
常討論的議題
Okay, finally let's have some
はい、やっといくつかできました
in conclusion
結論
OK, I said it earlier
OK、前にも言いました
That is to say, backward countries
つまり後進国
to develop the economy
経済を発展させる
Yes, we can simply say three conditions
はい、簡単に言えるのは3つの条件です
the first is
一つ目は
external conditions
外部条件
You see, this depends on history
ほら、これは歴史に依存します
historical situation
歴史的状況
Sometimes there is no such condition
そういう条件がない場合もある
sometimes
時々
external conditions
外部条件
The second is whether you have this
2つ目は、これを持っているかどうかです
ability to drive development
開発を推進する能力
The third is what I just said
3つ目は今言ったことです
What I have been emphasizing here is that
私がここで強調してきたのは、
Will to develop
発展する意志
on the ruler
定規の上に
cooperating people
協力してくれる人たち
Do you have the will to promote development
開発を推進する意志はありますか
We can see that
それがわかります
Just in Taiwan in the early postwar period
ちょうど戦後初期の台湾で
There is such a cold war environment
冷戦環境がそこにはある
that is
あれは
America for
アメリカにとって
Under the layout of the cold war
冷戦の構図の下で
to contain the middle
真ん中を塞ぐ
The CCP is willing to support the Nationalist Government politically
中国共産党は国民政府を政治的に支持する用意がある
But give room for development economically
ただし、経済的に開発の余地を与える
So it's certainly an advantage
それは確かに利点です
At the same time, the Japanese colonial government laid a good foundation
同時に、日本の植民地政府は良い基盤を築きました
But the daily role of the Cold War environment
しかし冷戦環境の日常的な役割
Cannot fully explain Taiwan's development achievements
台湾の発展成果を十分に説明できない
Very important is a dynamic condition
非常に重要なのは動的な状態です
On the development of the main capacity and transformation of the new country
新しい国の主要な能力の開発と変革について
when we see it we say
それを見ると私たちは言います
Internship in the National Government of the Mainland
本土中央政府でのインターンシップ
It is still a relatively backward government
まだ比較的後進的な政府だ
It's... call it light modernization
それは...軽い近代化と呼んでください
It lacks the organizational capacity to effectively rule a vast continent
広大な大陸を効果的に統治するための組織能力が欠けている
Some people joke that its decree does not leave Nanjing
その法令は南京を離れないと冗談を言う人もいる
that maybe a little more
それはもう少しかもしれない
After moving to Taiwan, the national government
台湾に移った後、国民党政府は
Retreat to 10% at the expense of the central government
中央政府の負担で10％に後退する
it has accumulated enough talent
十分な才能が蓄積されている
The experience of failure and the motivation for development
失敗の経験と成長の原動力
I think this fits with the foundation left by Japan
これは日本が残した基盤に合致していると思います
U.S. assistance made this development possible
米国の援助によりこの開発が可能になった
But what I want to emphasize is that
しかし、私が強調したいのは、
The will of the subject's dynamic development is still the key
被験者のダイナミックな発展の意志が依然として鍵となる
Let's look at the Philippines from 1950
1950 年のフィリピンを見てみましょう
The income of reinforcements is higher than that of Taiwan to this day
今でも援軍収入は台湾より高い
Their financial woes, then I guess it goes without saying.
彼らの経済的苦境は言うまでもないと思います。
I think this is his condition.
これが彼の状態だと思います。
very lacking
非常に不足しています
Well, knowing this comparison allows us to understand where we come from
さて、この比較を知ることで、私たちがどこから来たのかを理解することができます
Then I hope this helps us
それなら、これがお役に立てば幸いです
where can we go
どこに行こうか
Good Jingyuan
グッド・ジンユアン
In Taiwan's democratization process
台湾の民主化プロセスにおいて
The transformation of the developmental state has not been entirely successful
発達状態の変革は完全には成功していない
not totally unsuccessful but not totally successful
完全に失敗したわけではないが、完全に成功したわけでもない
that is
あれは
Because once when I was talking about these issues
なぜなら、かつて私がこれらの問題について話していたとき、
someone just said
誰かが今言った
Yes, democratization has these problems
はい、民主化にはこれらの問題があります
But are we going back to authoritarian rule?
しかし、私たちは権威主義的な支配に戻るのでしょうか？
What I say is definitely not anti-historical.
私の言うことは決して反歴史的ではありません。
as if we had a choice
あたかも私たちに選択肢があるかのように
Press a button again, democratic authority
もう一度ボタンを押してください、民主的権威
It means that of course we have to review at any time
もちろんいつでも見直しをしなければならないということです
review what we have done
私たちが行ったことを見直す
did not do well
うまくいきませんでした
Then we will be able to solve our problem shall not
そうすれば問題は解決できるでしょう
Then our predicament needs no explanation
そうすれば、私たちの苦境は説明の必要はありません
Everyone should feel that we are at least economically
少なくとも経済的には余裕があると誰もが感じるべきです
is in a bind
窮地に陥っている
I have said more about this part elsewhere.
この部分については別のところで詳しく述べました。
I'll just say it here
ここだけ言っておきます
Just in the first thirty years it was a
最初の 30 年間だけでも、
economic development in command
経済発展を指揮する
You can see that such a crisis is
このような危機が起きていることがわかります。
Steady by overcoming fear
恐怖を乗り越えて安定する
but to develop
しかし発展するために
Of course development is priority
もちろん開発が優先です
This dynamic over everything else is very clear
他のすべてに対するこの力関係は非常に明白です
But with the development of society and economic development
しかし、社会の発展や経済の発展に伴い、
Of course this has to be adjusted
もちろんこれは調整する必要があります
But in the process of democratization
しかし民主化の過程で
These adjustments were not very successful
これらの調整はあまり成功しませんでした
A compromise between other social requirements and development goals
他の社会的要件と開発目標との間の妥協点
We're very partisan right now
私たちは今非常に党派的です
so this
したがって、この
and the denial of developmentalism
そして開発主義の否定
not easy
比較不容易
At least not yet
少なくともまだ
create a reasonable
合理的なものを作成する
policy formation model
政策形成モデル
Because of the policy we of course have to be a compromise
ポリシーがあるので、当然妥協しなければなりません
you can't tell me today
今日は言えないね
all nuclear power
全ての原子力
then we
それから私たち
What do you rely on to generate electricity, right?
電気を生成するには何に頼っていますか?
you must
絶対です
there is a fold
有一個折衝好
do you have a time table
時刻表はありますか
are you
あなたは
what price to pay
どのような代償を払うべきか
Are you willing to do it?
やる気はありますか？
do we have a time table
タイムテーブルはありますか
you must have a punch
あなたはパンチを持っている必要があります
Economic Development and Environmental Protection
経済発展と環境保護
can only be a fold
折り目しかありません
Then we must have a society to compare
それなら比較する社会が必要だ
develop a more reasonable
より合理的な開発を行う
a process acceptable to all
誰もが受け入れられるプロセス
to form such a policy
そのような方針を立てるために
But we all know now
しかし、私たちは今では誰もが知っています
One is a more partisan
1人はより党派的だ
Not able to have a rational dialogue
合理的な対話ができない
Okay, here's what I'm going to say
さて、ここで私が言いたいのは
I originally talked about the problem of the colonial regime
私はもともと植民地体制の問題について話しました
this is us
これが私たちです
In the mainstream discourse of this society
この社会の主流の言説では
nativism
排外主義
is to be a bit
それは少しである
we can say is a
と言えます
Taiwan's New Nationalism
台湾の新たなナショナリズム
to build an independent country
独立した国を築くために
It turned out to be anti-KMT
反国民党であることが判明した
what about now
今はどう
Just break the rules and be anti-China
ルールを破って反中国になれ
this gets in our way
これは私たちの邪魔になります
to build a
を構築する
Lack of incentives to drive economic development
経済発展を促進するインセンティブの欠如
difficult to construct
建設が難しい
Viable vision of economic development
経済発展の実現可能なビジョン
at the same time
同時
Now the KMT
今では国民党が
there is no discussion
議論はありません
There is no way to be sure of your own history
自分の歴史を確かめる方法はない
no way to position myself
自分の立場を確立する方法がない
There is no way to find a new motivation
新しいモチベーションを見つける方法はない
I was talking about this
このことについて話していました
It was said during the colonial regime
植民地時代に言われてた
that is
あれは
i was talking about this
このことについて話していました
by
に
Inherited the Chinese nationalism of the old Wang Tucheng
老王土成の中国ナショナリズムを継承
In the process of promoting Taiwan's early economic development
台湾の早期経済発展を促進する過程で
I just explained
説明したばかりです
such a nationalism
そんなナショナリズム
Let them have a clear vision
明確なビジョンを持たせる
That vision is to industrialize Taiwan
そのビジョンは台湾を工業化することです
i just said
私はちょうど言いました
To complete the establishment of Taiwan as soon as possible
一日も早く台湾建国を完了するために
The great cause of modern industrial production system
近代工業生産システムの大きな原因
so they have a clear vision
彼らは明確なビジョンを持っています
This vision goes hand in hand with saying
このビジョンは次の言葉と密接に関連しています。
We want to foster our own industry
独自の産業を育てたい
own business
自身のビジネス
We want to learn from foreign capital
外資から学びたい
We have to learn from Europe and the United States
私たちはヨーロッパとアメリカから学ばなければなりません
but we also need to protect
しかし、私たちは守る必要もあります
protection complete
保護完了
Protection is limited
保護には限界がある
but we are open
でも私たちは開いています
but there is a process
しかしプロセスがあります
so you have means and ends
だからあなたには手段と目的がある
Then why do you need protection?
では、なぜ保護が必要なのでしょうか？
wait a minute because of foreign capital
外資だからちょっと待って
Let me grow up and I will open again
成長させてください、そうすればまた開きます
so
それで
So your democracy has a clear effect
つまり、あなたの民主主義は明らかな効果をもたらしています
you are the advanced threat
あなたは高度な脅威です
wait at the door
ドアのところで待ってて
I grow up and I open up again
私は成長して再び心を開く
So this is the role of economic democracy
これが経済民主主義の役割です
You face advanced foreign forces
先進的な外国軍と対峙する
Then you want to develop your strength
それなら自分の力を伸ばしたい
but
しかし
but now
でも今
The mainstream discourse that we have developed in the process of democratization
民主化の過程で私たちが発展させてきた主流の言説
First with the Kuomintang as the enemy
まずは国民党を敵に
Said it was a colonial regime, a foreign regime
それは植民地政権だ、外国政権だと言った
So it is an approach to social augmentation
つまり、これは社会的拡張へのアプローチです
now what i want to say is
今私が言いたいのは
The economic power of mainland China is not higher than that of Taiwan
中国本土の経済力は台湾の経済力より高くない
And it has not yet entered Taiwan
そして台湾にはまだ入っていない
So in an economic sense
つまり経済的な意味で
speak up
声を上げて
did not infringe Taiwan's interests
台湾の利益を侵害しなかった
That
それか
So one like this
それで、このようなもの
New nationalism targets anti-China
新たなナショナリズムは反中国をターゲットにする
There is no way to help us build a
私たちが構築するのを助ける方法はありません
A Vision for Future Economic Development
将来の経済発展のビジョン
ok so i think
わかりました、そう思います
just cut off the past history
過去の歴史を断ち切るだけ
difficult to understand the past
過去を理解するのは難しい
don't know how we got here
どうやってここに来たのか分からない
We must go back to the thread of history
私たちは歴史の糸に戻らなければなりません
redefine
再定義する
For all the people in Taiwan as one
台湾のすべての人々が一つになるために
economic community
経済界
How do we define our interests
自分の興味をどう定義するか
Then seek to build a shared vision
次に、共通のビジョンを構築しようとします
the middle
真ん中
one we have to face
私たちが直面しなければならないこと
the problem is that
問題はそれです
How to face in this process
このプロセスにどう対処するか
Taiwan's relationship with mainland China
台湾と中国本土の関係
It doesn't matter
それは問題ではありません
that part
その部分
this part
この部分
i must say
私は言わなければならない
our current thinking
私たちの現在の考え
The ideas in the mainstream discourse of this society
この社会の主流の言説における考え方
With Taiwan's early national government
台湾の初期の国民政府と
The pro-American and anti-communist discourses are highly similar to
親米と反共産主義の言説は非常に似ています。
That's what I just said
それが私が今言ったことです
that is to say we
つまり私たちは
In the course of this discussion
この議論の過程で
because
なぜなら
the national government
中央政府
After being a colonial and foreign regime
植民地および外国政権を経て
Our role with respect to the United States and Japan
米国と日本に対する私たちの役割
There is no way to review positively
肯定的にレビューする方法はありません
So our position for ourselves
つまり、私たち自身の立場
In fact, there is no way to review it positively.
実際、それを肯定的にレビューする方法はありません。
I am
私は
I'm over time
時間が過ぎてしまった
Then I mainly think
それから私は主に考えます
if we do these things
これらのことをやれば
will help us
私たちを助けてくれるでしょう
start again
再開する
help us go
行くのを手伝ってください
It is more reasonable to face cross-strait relations
両岸関係に直面する方が合理的だ
If we don't face it with this attitude
この姿勢で向き合わなければ
If you look at history and understand these relationships from history
歴史を見て、歴史からこれらの関係を理解すると
It's hard for us to find our way
私たちにとって道を見つけるのは難しい
ok then i will stop here
わかりました、それではここでやめます
Thank you Professor Ji Wang for reinterpreting the development of Taiwan's modeling economy
台湾のモデル経済の発展を再解釈してくださったJi Wang教授に感謝します
Is there any problem with the rest of the time?
残りの時間は問題ないでしょうか？
We can probably accommodate three or five questions
おそらく 3 つまたは 5 つの質問に対応できるでしょう
come please
来てください
In fact, I think this speech started from the Republic of China
実際、この演説は中華民国から始まったと思います
Here
ここ
I found from your paper that there are two main axes
あなたの論文から主な軸が 2 つあることがわかりました
one is national
1つは国民的です
Or the Republic of China we are talking about now
あるいは今話している中華民国についても
introduce myself
自己紹介する
When I talk about the whole context, it sounds like
全体の文脈について話すと、次のように聞こえます。
From the Republic of China to Taiwan in 1945
1945年に中華民国から台湾へ
But the final conclusion is that
しかし、最終的な結論は、
Find the bottleneck of development from the history
歴史から開発のボトルネックを見つける
It actually sounds like the bottleneck is still there.
実際のところ、ボトルネックはまだ存在しているようです。
Where is the bottleneck?
ボトルネックはどこですか?
That is to say at the end
つまり最後に
You said this KMT KMT
あなたはこう言いました国民党国民党
it doesn't affirm itself
それ自体を肯定するわけではない
In fact, it has always been very sure of its status
実際、それは常に自分のステータスを非常に確信していました
That is to say it ignores a thing
つまり、何かを無視します
because it's from 1945 until now
1945年から今までのことだから
it does not readjust to a new social situation
新しい社会状況に再適応しない
Actually it is not without certainty
実は確実性がないわけではない
100 years since its founding
創業100年
Including the Republic of China you are using now
現在使用している中華民国を含む
This is all affirmation of itself
これはすべて自分自身の肯定です
That is, is it not retuned
つまり戻されていないのか
Forty years of development
40年にわたる開発
I'm still going to escape from that old stalk
私はまだその古い茎から逃げるつもりです
It's like saying what you just said
さっき言ったことを言っているようなものだ
Canan Ogun of this Hatta raincoat
このハッタのレインコートのカナン・オグン
that's not a
それはそうではありません
that's not a term that everyone is familiar with
それは誰もがよく知っている用語ではありません
But that is to say, later we slowly discovered from this memory
しかし、つまり、後になって私たちはこの記憶からゆっくりと発見したのです
Hatta Rain
ハッタレイン
That is naturally related to the so-called Shimen Reservoir
それは当然、いわゆる石門貯水池と関係しています。
I think it's a fact that everyone knows
誰もが知っている事実だと思います
The second is to say
2つ目は、こう言うことです
talking about
について話す
Does capitalism have to be managed locally?
資本主義はローカルで管理されなければならないのでしょうか？
I think this is a
これは
For example, for example
たとえば、たとえば
Japan has completed from 1895 to 1945
日本は1895年から1945年まで完成しました
Three-quarters of Taiwan's so-called railways
台湾のいわゆる鉄道の 4 分の 3
Then KMT probably only played a quarter
それでは国民党はおそらく4分の1しかプレーしなかったでしょう
But he spent 20 or 30 years playing
しかし、彼は20年か30年をプレーして過ごしました
I think
私が思うに
Now
現在
Does capitalism follow local management?
資本主義は地域経営に従うのか？
ask this so-called
いわゆるこれを尋ねます
A group of elites emerged after the war
戦後に出現したエリート集団
Actually they are
実際、彼らはそうです
not on the ground
地上ではない
Might be someone from the provinces running this thing
地方の誰かがこれを運営しているかもしれない
so i was thinking
それで私は考えていました
The things received are not only Taiwan Bank, Taiwan Sugar, and Taiwan Railway
受け取ったものは台湾銀行、台湾糖業、台湾鉄道だけではありません
Anyway, many things were operated at that time
とにかく当時は色々な物が運用されていました
One question I want to explore is that
私が検討したい質問の 1 つは、
when we are in this understanding
私たちがこの理解の中にあるとき
Or split it into two articles
または 2 つの記事に分割する
National Japanese Occupation period
日本統治時代
Also, the identification between us is obvious
また、私たちの間の同一性は明らかです
We are in this serious speech
私たちはこの真剣なスピーチの中にいます
We've got a so-called non-consensus position
私たちはいわゆる非合意の立場をとっています
I'm also talking briefly
私も簡単に話しています
If it's not clear, we'll talk later, thank you
ご不明な点がございましたら、後ほどお話しいたしますので、よろしくお願いいたします
but i thank you for your opinion
でもあなたの意見には感謝します
But I don't understand what your problem is
しかし、あなたの質問の意味がわかりません
my question is that
私の質問はそれです
modern capitalism
現代資本主義
You just said he must be operating locally
彼は地元で活動しているに違いないと言ったばかりです
For example, during the Japanese occupation period, many of his consortiums were from Japanese consortiums.
たとえば、日本統治時代には、彼のコンソーシアムの多くは日本のコンソーシアムからのものでした。
right so that no longer does not constitute the so-called
いわゆる権利を構成しないものとなります。
During the Japanese occupation period, it has entered a modern national system
日本統治時代に近代化された国家体制に移行
Or it has already entered the capital system. Then, during the Japanese occupation period, there were many American
あるいはすでに資本主義に入っており、日本統治時代にはアメリカ人も多かった。
The situation may be such an example of the Taiwanese operating distance
この状況は台湾の営業距離の一例かもしれません
the things you just said at the beginning
あなたが冒頭で言ったこと
I'm starting from here is to say
ここから始めるということは、
Hong Kong is also run by Hong Kong people
香港も香港人によって運営されている
But he is completely reborn as a Lord of the East
しかし彼は完全に東方の領主として生まれ変わる。
My point is this
私のポイントはこれです
I'm good, let me take a look at what you mean
大丈夫です、あなたの言いたいことを見てみましょう
That is to say, capitalism should not be localized
つまり、資本主義は局所化すべきではない
the answer is yes
答えははいです
you have to develop
あなたは開発しなければなりません
your own industry your own business
自分の業界、自分のビジネス
Hon Hai
鴻海
He is an industry in Taiwan, and after he developed it, he
彼は台湾の産業であり、それを発展させた後、
Other current continents
他現在大陸
employ nearly 800,000 people
80万人近くを雇用する
But his company headquarters and R&D are still located in Taiwan
しかし、彼の本社と研究開発は依然として台湾にあります。
so
それで
So the mainland will still detect it as a Taiwanese company
したがって、本土では依然として台湾企業として検出されるでしょう。
I answered your question like this
あなたの質問にこのように答えました
That is to say, if we the Red Sea
つまり、私たちが紅海だとしたら、
If there is no development of the Red Sea
紅海の開発がなければ
Waiting for Taiwan, for example, processing and exporting
加工・輸出など台湾待ち
After the foreign capital left
外資が撤退した後
There are no companies in Taiwan
台湾には会社がない
But we have developed high technology
しかし、私たちは高度な技術を開発しました
Then although the Red Sea moved a lot of production outside
その後、紅海によって多くの生産物が外部に移動しましたが、
but it still leaves a lot
でもまだたくさん残ってる
So in Taiwan's high-tech industry
台湾のハイテク産業では
still have a certain size
まだある程度の大きさがある
So I guess this is
それで、これはそうだと思います
It is the localized development of capitalism
それは資本主義の局地的発展です
I don't know if this answers your question
これがあなたの質問の答えになるかどうかわかりません
ok who else
わかりました、他に誰がいますか
please
お願いします
ask the professor
教授に聞く
Our Taiwan technology is in the world
私たちの台湾の技術は世界にあります
is a very important part of the exhibition
展覧会の非常に重要な部分です
Please tell me next time we are in Taiwan
今度台湾に行くときは教えてください
Can be used internationally like our technology
当社の技術と同様に国際的に使用可能
what kind of business would it be thank you
どのようなビジネスになりますか、ありがとう
the answer is not easy
答えは簡単ではありません
I have a look
見てみましょう
Our development in the last ten years
過去10年間の当社の発展
that does
それはそうなる
I think it's more worrying
もっと心配だと思うよ
That is to say, for our high-tech
つまり、私たちのハイテク技術については、
growing since
以來越來越大
For example, the past ten years
例えばここ10年くらい
If we look at manufacturing
ものづくりに目を向けてみると
its distribution ratio
その分配率
the whole broad
全体的に広い
share of the high-tech industry
ハイテク産業のシェア
has reached nearly half
半分近くに達しました
other industries
他産業
Manufacturing is in decline
製造業は衰退している
not that their share
彼らの取り分ではない
Decreasing high-tech industry is increasing
衰退するハイテク産業が増加中
never happened before this
これまでに一度も起こったことはありません
In the past, there were real and some minus
過去にはリアルもあればマイナスもあった
Taiwan is at least
台湾は少なくとも
Is it a comparison, or a relatively balanced one, one time
比較というか、比較的バランスがとれたものでしょうか、一回。
an economy but in the last ten years
過去10年間の経済
Our dependence on high technology is high to a very high level
私たちのハイテクへの依存度は非常に高いレベルに達しています
but if you say it again
でももう一度言うなら
So you said there's not much room for growth
だから成長の余地はあまりないって言ってたね
i didn't say that
私はそんなことは言いませんでした
because this means this
これはこういう意味だから
It is also an opportunity for Taiwan to have such development.
台湾もこういう発展ができるのですね
also lucky
幸運でもあります
That is, because the high-tech industry is a
つまり、ハイテク産業は
In a growing global
成長するグローバルの中で
Because Taiwan can participate in this
台湾も参加できるので
this whole world
この世界全体
just how to say
ちょうどどのように言うか
it's still going on
それはまだ続いています
is the frontier of the world
世界のフロンティアです
cutting edge
最先端
He is still pushing forward
彼は今も前進し続けている
Then Taiwan can also participate
そうすれば台湾も参加できる
Then this piece is constantly expanding
そしてこの作品は常に拡大し続けています
So Taiwan is lucky
だから台湾は幸運だ
able to continue to participate in this
継続して参加できる
Although it is said that profits continue to become microblogging
ミニブログ化して利益が出続けていると言われていますが
But this production also has a lot of external shifts
しかし、この作品には外部からの変化もたくさんあります
but
しかし
But Taiwan can continue to participate in this industry
しかし、台湾はこの産業に参加し続けることができる
It's our grades and luck
それは私たちの成績と運です
Then I think it has a wiki feel
それならwikiっぽい感じだと思います
but not to say
でも言わないで
It is also difficult for us to say that this ratio is too high.
この比率が高すぎるとも言い難い。
won't grow anymore
もう成長しません
is not what it means
それが意味するものではありません
high tech industry
ハイテク産業
will continue to grow
成長し続けます
that just means
それはただの意味です
we go over this
私たちはこれを検討します
The policy approach to combating fear is to say
恐怖を克服するための政策アプローチは次のとおりです。
Well, then our twenty years later
さて、それでは私たちの20年後
where are the growth industries
成長産業はどこにあるのか
this batch
このバッチ
This group of old people said they would keep asking such questions
この老人たちのグループは、今後もそのような質問をすると言いました
That
それか
But this space where the world grows
でも世界が広がるこの空間
That is, I am not just talking about Taiwan
つまり、私は台湾のことだけを話しているのではありません。
the whole world
世界全体です
as far as we mortals can see
私たち定命の者が見る限り
seems to grow limited
成長が制限されているようです
For example, countries in the world that want to develop
例えば、世界の発展を望む国々は、
have invested a lot of resources in the biotechnology industry
バイオテクノロジー産業に多くのリソースを投資してきました
Just like our Academia Sinica also invested a lot of resources
私たちの中央研究院も多くのリソースを投資したのと同じように、
But the biotech industry
しかし、バイオテクノロジー業界は、
On the one hand you can say that you also have to vote
一方で、投票する必要があるとも言えます。
because of global competition
グローバル競争のせいで
you can't be absent
欠席することはできません
But the biotech industry is a
しかし、バイオテクノロジー産業は、
impossible to play such an important role
そんな重要な役割を果たすのは不可能だ
i must say
私は言わなければならない
because of his employment
彼の雇用のせいで
His employment density is so low
彼の雇用密度は非常に低い
It is impossible for him to go to the mainland like Hon Hai
鴻海のように本土に行くのは無理だ
Care for 800,000 people
80万人をケア
Then go and say it's going to reach a million people
それから行って、100万人に届くと言ってください
Although this means that many of his workers will commit suicide
これは彼の従業員の多くが自殺することを意味しますが、
but anyway
とにかく
He has provided such a large amount of employment
彼はこれほど多くの雇用を提供してきた
The biotech industry is impossible
バイオ産業は無理だ
No matter how it grows, it cannot have such a function
どんなに成長してもそんな機能は持たない
So I think for the biotech industry we have to understand
したがって、バイオテクノロジー業界にとって私たちは理解する必要があると思います
As if there is no way we can't miss out on global competition
まるで世界的な競争に負けるわけにはいかないかのように
But we can't be based on such a big backward look
しかし、私たちはそのような大きな後ろ向きの見方に基づいて行動することはできません
Because of its employment volume, the value it generates is limited
雇用量が多いため、生み出される価値には限界がある
and is assuming that you can develop
そしてあなたが開発できると仮定しています
Then there is another one in Taiwan. Is there one that can be said?
それから台湾にももう一つありますが、言えるものはありますか。
Comparable to yours with this technology
このテクノロジーであなたのものに匹敵します
The kind of business that can grow again
再び成長できるビジネスの種類
I don't think we are quite
私たちは完全ではないと思います
we can't say
私たちは言えません
but i think there are some
でもいくつかあると思う
as far as Taiwan
台湾まで
But there are industries that have the ability to follow
しかし、これに続く能力を備えた業界もある
For example, what is possible
例えば、どんなことが可能かというと、
What future industry is the United States developing?
米国はどのような未来産業を発展させようとしているのでしょうか?
Taiwan has the opportunity to participate and follow up
台湾には参加とフォローアップの機会がある
I think this part is that we can actually have this ability
この部分は私たちが実際にこの能力を身につけることができるということだと思います
But I think our biggest challenge is
しかし、私たちの最大の課題は
Can we be more active in business
もっと積極的にビジネスに取り組めるでしょうか
Use the mainland market with the mainland
本土で本土市場を利用する
What kind of cooperative development should we do at a relatively high level?
比較的高いレベルでどのような協力開発を行うべきでしょうか？
For example, Taiwan's high-tech manufacturers have their status
例えば、台湾のハイテクメーカーはその地位を確立しています。
Although the mainland government is very courageous
本土政府は非常に勇敢ですが
But with its courage, there is no way to support high-tech members
しかし、その勇気ではハイテクメンバーをサポートする方法はありません
Of course you can see that there are all kinds of possibilities
もちろん、あらゆる種類の可能性があることがわかります
So far, Taiwanese businessmen have gone to the mainland alone
これまでのところ、台湾のビジネスマンは単独で大陸に渡っている
able to develop very limited
非常に限られた開発しかできない
But fields like this
しかし、このようなフィールド
we see some possibilities
いくつかの可能性が見えてきます
But this must be a high level of difficulty
でもこれはかなり難易度が高いはず
What kind of binocular strategy will be developed by the senior level with social support
上級レベルは社会的支援を得てどのような両眼視戦略を策定するか
thank you teacher
ありがとう、先生
That one is my personal forward advice
それは私からの個人的な前向きなアドバイスです
what we just talked about
私たちが今話したこと
Taiwan's 60-person economy
台湾の60人経済
Of course, the Kuomintang has a lot of technical officials.
もちろん国民党には技術官僚がたくさんいる。
and very talented
そしてとても才能のある
But Taiwan's CNC is simply
しかし、台湾の CNC は単純に
I think it provides a lot of motivation
とてもモチベーションが上がると思います
The one who came out of the mountain in 1948 was the 37th year of Mongolia
1948年に山から出てきたのはモンゴル建国37年目
So from this world in the process of my study
だから勉強の途中でこの世から
After an official full from us tell us what the 375 checkout is
弊社から正式な連絡があった後、375 チェックアウトとは何かをお知らせください
And the Kuomintang beautifies the tigers very much
そして国民党は虎をとても美化します
I heard Wen Mao Mao is the landlord
ウェン・マオ・マオが家主だと聞いた
My dad is a mother
私の父は母です
So the mother may benefit as well.
そのため、母親にもメリットがあるかもしれません。
But the landlord is God's beloved
しかし家主は神の最愛の人です
Mother
母親
So when the Kuomintang detected 375
つまり、国民党が375を検出したとき
He said this private land
彼はこの私有地を言った
In less than a year, he immediately included four Taiwan dollars in a box
1 年も経たないうちに、彼はすぐに 4 台湾ドルを箱に入れました
So Yuan Guo said what he said is the history of our past dynasties.
そこで袁国は、自分の言ったことは我々の過去の王朝の歴史だ、と言いました。
Centralize the country's resources to redistribute
国の資源を一元化して再分配する
But I've concentrated a lot of motivation during this time
でもこの間、たくさんのモチベーションを集中させてきた
But from our official 375 checkout beautification
しかし、公式の 375 チェックアウトからの美化
I have visited Ma Guoshidu Taiwan several times for examination materials.
私は試験資料のために馬国士度台湾を何度か訪れたことがあります。
Come to the country, the Democratic Party can do it when they go back
田舎に来い、民主党は帰ったらできるよ
In addition, for this three-dimensional, if you can do a kind of data research on it
また、この三次元について、ある種のデータ調査をしていただければと思います。
What kind of benefits does this provide to Taiwan, and what kind of cloth number does it offset?
これは台湾にどのような利益をもたらし、どのような布地番号を相殺するのでしょうか?
So becoming Taiwan is until now every election, I still regard this as a hype topic
だから、台湾になるのは今まで選挙のたびだったけど、私は今でも誇大宣伝のテーマだと思っている
It is also the differences in the policy consciousness of the people in the north and south of Taiwan
それは台湾の北と南の人々の政策意識の違いでもある
So I think we should have the manpower to study him and announce this
したがって、私たちは彼を研究し、これを発表する人材を確保すべきだと思います
Because I think he made the boar view too glorified
猪の見方を美化しすぎたと思うから
Because I want to get first-hand information about this influence from the public security side, from the public security side.
警察から国民へのこの影響について直接の情報を得たいからです。
That's a big gap with Gongying's information.
それはゴンインの情報との大きなギャップです。
And Dongying's information is very vague
東営の情報は非常に曖昧です
Just like Ou Ba, Hideo has never been sad
王婆と同じように、ヒデオは一度も悲しいことをしたことがない
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you, I think this land reform depends on whether you want to ask the landlord or the electric farmer
ありがとう、この土地改革はあなたが地主に頼むか電気農家に頼むかによって決まると思います
the answer will be very good
答えはとても良いでしょう
both sides for me
私にとってはどちらの側も
Is the answer different?
答えは違うのでしょうか？
I'm not saying now that I'm going to hold him accountable
私は今、彼の責任を追及するとは言っていない
Are you announcing this fact?
この事実を公表していますか？
because of his
彼のせいで
well i can only answer briefly
まあ、私は簡単に答えることしかできません
My first answer is that I think
私の最初の答えは次のとおりです
because that is a very clear
それはとても明らかだから
how to say clearly
はっきり言う方法
Violation of private property rights
私有財産権の侵害
go with the power of the country
国の力に従う
move to private property rights
私有財産権への移行
The first is to pick up rent
まずは家賃の受け取りです
The second is to expropriate land
2つ目は土地の収用です
and then distributed to electric farmers
その後、電力農家に配布
so i thought
ので、私は考えました
Of course he violated the interests of the landlord
もちろん地主の利益を侵害した
right
右
So it's a strange thing that a landowner would approve of that.
ですから、地主がそれを認めるというのはおかしな話です。
So the landlords borrow Taiwan dollars when they come
それで家主は来たら台湾ドルを借ります
Electric farmers pay different regulatory NT dollars
電気農家は異なる規制上の台湾ドルを支払っている
cut this picture back
この写真を切り戻します
no no no
ダメダメダメ
At that time, the three-seven-five cutting beads were changing
その頃、三・七・五のカッティングビーズは変わりつつあった
The first phase of Sanqiwu Jianzhu was in 1949
Sanqiwu Jianzhu の最初の段階は 1949 年でした
was changing at that time
その時は変わっていた
In terms of Taiwan dollars New Taiwan dollars
台湾ドルの場合 新台湾ドル
He is 11 months less than a year
彼は1年未満11か月です
It seems that in less than a year, there will be no NT dollars
あと1年以内に台湾ドルがなくなるらしい
New Taiwan dollar same year
同年新台湾ドル
1949 Two Things Doing Together
1949 二つのことを一緒に行う
From the first phase to 1949, the first phase to making three seven five cut beads
第一期から1949年まで 三七五カットビーズを作るまで
then in summer
それから夏に
I forgot which month
何月か忘れた
seems like november
11月のようです
Is there still something like that Linma in it?
リンマのようなものはまだありますか？
This NTD is in the Danhua rules
このNTDは丹華ルールに含まれています
well, the details we can't talk about here
まあ、詳細はここでは話せませんが、
but i think that is
でもそれはそうだと思う
Let me tell you about his effect
彼の効果についてお話しましょう
His very important effect is
彼の非常に重要な効果は、
He forced an end to landownership by coercive force
彼は強制力によって地主権を強制的に終わらせた
Because landlord economy means
大家経済というのは
social elite
社会的エリート
not saying good or bad
良いとも悪いとも言わない
Because China has been like this for thousands of years
中国は何千年も前からこんな感じだから
That is, it is a traditional landlord economy
つまり、伝統的な地主経済です。
This is the landlord world
これが地主の世界です
This official is your imperial examination to become an official
この官吏は官吏になるための科挙です
This is a Chinese system
これは中国のシステムです
but you i just said
でもあなたは今言ったばかりです
It's CO's bourgeois revolution
それはCOのブルジョワ革命です
It just took hundreds of years
ただ何百年もかかった
The feudal is the feudal aristocracy
封建制とは封建的貴族制度のことです
and this land of the Church
そしてこの教会の地
and the privilege exited
そして特権は終了しました
Then began a capitalist economy
その後資本主義経済が始まりました
the land reform
土地改革
It is also a top-down
それもトップダウンです
bourgeois revolution
ブルジョワ革命
so it ended the landlord economy
それで地主経済は終わった
It means that the elites of society can no longer rely on
それは社会のエリートがもはや頼ることができないことを意味します
This landlord is very good
この家主はとても良い人です
I'll go, I'll buy land if I have money
行きます、お金があれば土地を買います
then landowner
それから地主
as a means of livelihood for the elite of this society
この社会のエリートたちの生計手段として
This is the past landlord
こちらは元大家さん
the past economy
過去の経済
Our traditional agricultural economy
私たちの伝統的な農業経済
The Economy of China's Agricultural Society
中国農業社会の経済
the existing model
の既存のモデル
we can't say
私たちは言えません
he must
他一定
call it morally bad
それを道徳的に悪いと言う
i think it's historical
それは歴史的だと思う
glasses of history
歴史の眼鏡
but you are under pressure from the west
しかしあなたは西側からの圧力を受けています
you
あなた
Everybody thinks we have to industrialize
工業化する必要があると誰もが考えている
we have to get into a
私たちは入る必要があります
this different era
この違う時代
that this
これは
What the national government did
国政府がやったこと
the land reform
土地改革
has an effect
効果がある
Regardless of the process will definitely
どのような過程であっても必ず
Will
意思
The interests of the landlord must be damaged
家主の利益が損なわれなければならない
big small
大的小的
Of course there are varying degrees
もちろん程度の差はありますが
must be damaged
損傷している必要があります
But Diannong
しかし、ディアノン
Of course some electric farmers benefit
もちろん一部の電気農家は恩恵を受けています
that this
これは
but more importantly
しかし、もっと重要なことは
it is an era
それは時代です
changes in the times
時代の変化
It forces the economy of Taiwan into a different era
台湾経済を別の時代に押し込む
At the same time, the national government is also under greater pressure
同時に、政府への圧力も高まっている
Because the elite of your society can no longer live as landlords
なぜなら、社会のエリートはもはや地主として生きていくことはできないからです。
you have to give them a way out
あなたは彼らに出口を与えなければなりません
you must industrialize
工業化する必要がある
You must develop industry and commerce
産業と商業を発展させなければなりません
and let these people have a way out
そしてこの人たちに逃げ道を与えてください
So this is the meaning of his words age
これが彼の言葉の意味です
In this process, of course, there are gains and losses.
この過程では、当然、利益も損失も生じます。
no more questions
もう質問はありません
Thanks
ありがとう
Hello Professor, I have two questions
こんにちは、教授、質問が 2 つあります
The first one is the Taiwan Miracle mentioned at the beginning
一つ目は冒頭で述べた「台湾の奇跡」
including political miracles and economic miracles
政治的奇跡と経済的奇跡を含む
That kind of statement is Taiwan's economic development
そういう発言が台湾の経済発展なんだよ
democratization of politics with facilitation
円滑化による政治の民主化
May I ask if such a statement is established?
そのような記述が確立されているかどうかお聞きしてもいいでしょうか？
Can it be established?
成立するのか？
This is the first question
これが最初の質問です
The second question is mentioned in the introduction
2 番目の質問は「はじめに」で言及されています
professor you are right now
教授、あなたは今です
That is, the situation after the reform and opening up in contemporary China has been studied
つまり、現代中国における改革開放後の状況を研究したものである。
Assuming this statement is true
この発言が真実であると仮定すると、
Can we have such optimistic expectations for contemporary China?
現代の中国に対して、これほど楽観的な期待を持てるでしょうか？
because of economic development
経済発展のせいで
So will politics be more democratic or something like that?
それで政治はもっと民主的になるのでしょうか？
this is the second question
これは 2 番目の質問です
Thanks
ありがとう
ok very important question
わかりました、非常に重要な質問です
I think all backward countries
すべての後進国だと思います
when he started
彼が始めたとき
His politics must be rights protection
彼の政治は権利保護でなければならない
is that it should be a common phenomenon
それは一般的な現象であるはずだということです
there is no reason
理由はない
he is not an activist
彼は活動家ではありません
that economic development
その経済発展
He will surely educate many
彼はきっと多くの人を教育するだろう
Get a lot of independent economic resources
独立した経済資源をたくさん手に入れる
Then the economy develops better
そうすれば経済はより良く発展する
The more individuals with independent economic resources
独立した経済資源を持つ個人が増えるほど
Everyone's education level has improved
みんなの教育レベルが上がった
improved living standards
生活水準の向上
So the economy grows
それで経済は成長する
they want to get involved in politics
彼らは政治に関与したいと考えています
the right to participate in politics
政治に参加する権利
desire will be higher
欲望はさらに高まるだろう
So the better your economy develops
したがって、経済が発展すればするほど、
It is the desire of some people and the existing political
それは一部の人々と既存の政治の願望です
The higher the tension in the rights-defending political system will be
権利を擁護する政治制度の緊張が高まるほど、
so
それで
but
しかし
but what happens between
しかし、その間に何が起こるのか
That is to say it is not a necessity
つまり必需品ではない
What I just said is inevitable
私が今言ったことは避けられない
That is to say, the tension between
つまり、間の緊張は、
pressure on the existing political system
既存の政治システムに対する圧力
The pressure to change will be stronger
変化へのプレッシャーが強くなる
but
しかし
But there is no necessity in this
しかし、これには必然性はありません
say it will
そうなるだろうと言う
what must happen
何が起こらなければならないのか
for example
例えば
Taiwan and South Korea are relatively successful examples
台湾と韓国は比較的成功した例
That
それか
For example, we see that Thailand A does not seem to be so
たとえば、タイ A はそうではないことがわかります。
relatively less successful
比較的成功率が低い
that we can
私たちにできること
But Taiwan and South Korea
でも台湾と韓国は
also have different paths
違う道もあります
right
右
so i guess there is something inevitable
だから避けられない何かがあると思う
I just think what I just said is a kind of necessity
私が今言ったことは一種の必然だと思います
economic development
経済発展
The better it is, the greater the pressure on the existing authoritarian system
それが良くなればなるほど、既存の権威主義体制への圧力は大きくなる
But how will this road go
しかしこの道はどうなるのか
Depends on the existing conditions in each place
各地の現況による
So it's hard to say it's going to be one way or the other
したがって、どちらかの方向に進むとは言い難い
But we can say that the more average your original development
しかし、最初の発達が平均的であればあるほど、
more evenly distributed income
収入がより均等に分配される
Then the allocation of resources is more fair
そうすれば、リソースの割り当てはより公平になります
This democratization process should be better
この民主化プロセスはもっと良くなるはずだ
but I think there are many different factors
でも色々な要因があると思います
For example, if you spend two minutes talking
たとえば、2分間話すと、
That is to say Taiwan
つまり台湾
We have taken a more convenient path
私たちはより便利な道を選びました
we can just say yes
私たちはただ「はい」と言うことができます
a subject-based
主題ベースの
agree with the political path
政治的路線に同意する
This is also because the national government, in its authoritarian way,
これは、国家政府が権威主義的なやり方で、
I just said
私はちょうど言いました
The development of the economy in this military way
このような軍事的な方法による経済の発展
So the issue of that distribution is in Taiwan
つまり、その配布の問題は台湾にあります
hard to be a dominant
支配者になるのは難しい
to mobilize the people
人々を動員する
This income distribution is too unfair
この所得分配は不公平すぎる
or how
あるいはどうやって
this kind of issue
この種の問題
Assigned issues because
割り当てられた課題の理由
under authoritarian rule
権威主義的な統治下で
He has more or less dealt with
彼は多かれ少なかれ対処してきた
Therefore the issues of these assignments
したがって、これらの割り当ての問題は、
not easily provoked
簡単に誘発されない
to rally these forces of democratic opposition
これらの民主的反対勢力を結集させるために
But the politics of identity
しかし、アイデンティティの政治
It's easy to distinguish you from me
あなたと私を見分けるのは簡単です
is an easier path
より簡単な道です
So Taiwan has taken such a path
台湾はそのような道をたどったのですね
has its benefits
利点があります
has its downsides
欠点があります
south korean words
韓国の言葉
He's a very solid mobilizer
彼は非常に堅実な機動力のある選手だ
it's him
それは彼です
His most critical is 1987
彼の最も批判的な作品は 1987 年です
millions of students
何百万人もの学生
union what church
組合は何の教会ですか
Going to the street to have a bloody confrontation with the military and police
街頭に出て軍や警察と血みどろの衝突をする
that is a decisive
それは決定的なことだ
Then they were in the post-war student movement
彼らは戦後の学生運動に参加していた
they have very guild sports
彼らは非常にギルドスポーツを持っています
has his long-term foundation
彼の長期的な基盤がある
so you meet boy friends
それでボーイフレンドに会います
they are very proud
彼らはとても誇りに思っています
their civil society is very powerful
彼らの市民社会は非常に強力です
For example, like I met a friend
たとえば、友達に会ったときのように
He has a real NGO
彼は本物のNGOを持っている
They are supported by membership associations
彼らは会員協会によってサポートされています
Then there are 100 dedicated staff
そして100人の専任スタッフがいる
So-called NGOs in Taiwan
台湾のいわゆるNGO
I also know that there are full-time professionals with more than 100
また、100 人を超えるフルタイムの専門家がいることも知っています。
But they all rely on the government's position to report
しかし、それらはすべて政府の立場に依存して報告している
we don't have that strength
私たちにはそんな力はない
our so-called civil society
私たちのいわゆる市民社会
no such basis
そんな根拠はない
but the boy has
しかし少年は持っています
that's different
それならこれは違います
so
それで
but they paid a high price
しかし彼らは高い代償を払った
like i agree
私も同意するように
He said that your apartment is on the street
彼はあなたのアパートが路上にあると言いました
or what rights take to the streets
または路上でどのような権利が取られるか
Then I went back home for dinner
それから家に帰って食べました
He said we went to the streets when we were young
彼は、私たちが若い頃、街に行ったと言った
It's just that everyone's head is bleeding
ただ皆の頭から血が流れているだけだ
Go back to dorms
寮に戻りなさい
if you can go back
戻れるなら
So they pay different prices
したがって、彼らは異なる価格を支払います
that's what you paid for
それはあなたが支払ったものです
the foundation of your civil society
あなたの市民社会の基盤
it might be different
違うかもしれない
so i feel all the things
だから私はすべてを感じます
all have something to say
全員が何か言いたいことがある
So Taiwan South Korea
それで台湾韓国
we are very very
私たちはとてもとても
country of brothers
兄弟の国
postwar development of all
戦後のあらゆる発展
very very similar
とてもとても似ています
But we see this democratic path
しかし、私たちはこの民主的な道を見ます
not exactly the same
全く同じではない
Mainland China really dare not say
中国本土は本当に言いたくない
But I think that structure
でもその構造は、
we have now seen
私たちは今見ました
His developmental anger is very good
彼の発達的な怒りはとても良いです
very stressful
ストレスがたまる
with the existing system
既存のシステムで
But China is really big
しかし中国は本当に大きい
I can't go on anymore
もうこれ以上は続けられない
our time is up
私たちの時間は終わりました
We thank Professor Ju Wangwen with applause
朱王文教授に拍手で感謝します
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you for half a year
半年間ありがとうございました